<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Jekyll Bootstrap</title>
 <link href="http://username.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://username.github.com"/>
 <updated>2012-09-04T18:35:50-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://username.github.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Name Lastname</name>
   <email>blah@email.test</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Startup Law for Designers</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/startup-law-for-designers/index.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-31T06:40:23-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/startup-law-for-designers/startup-law-for-designers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://members.geekdom.com/events/52/&quot; title=&quot;Geekdom Startup Law Nathan Roach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; was given at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekdom.com&quot; title=&quot;Geekdom&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Geekdom&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative workspace/incubator for startups in San Antonio, Texas. It addresses many of the common questions that design shops and web startups encounter as they build their branding, select naming, and form a company. &amp;nbsp;I'm told a full streaming audio/video version will be available at some point, and I'll update this post if and when the Q/A portion is posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;object height=&quot;363&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://prezi.com/bin/preziloader.swf&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#ffffff&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;prezi_id=f194ad34773bb669eae658930efc6128e2a00c5a&amp;amp;lock_to_path=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&amp;amp;autoplay=no&amp;amp;autohide_ctrls=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://prezi.com/bin/preziloader.swf&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; flashvars=&quot;prezi_id=f194ad34773bb669eae658930efc6128e2a00c5a&amp;amp;lock_to_path=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&amp;amp;autoplay=no&amp;amp;autohide_ctrls=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also available in PDF format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[posterous-content:gxsAosyInvcaopuBxvhg]]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2012 Bexar Bench Motions Trials</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/2012-bexar-bench-motions-trials/index.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-18T01:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/2012-bexar-bench-motions-trials/2012-bexar-bench-motions-trials</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This presentation was given at the Bexar County Bench Motions and Trials continuing legal education seminar in May 2012. &amp;nbsp;Presenters are Judge Richard Price, Judge Cathy Stryker, and attorney Nathan Roach. &amp;nbsp;The presentation follows updates on the topic of e-discovery of Electronically Stored Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[posterous-content:gCoyjyolyacEfJnlxvCF]][[posterous-content:kFrofqFqqFvJkohbtyvD]]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Simple Methods and Tools for an Agile Law Practice</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/simple-methods-and-tools-for-an-agile-law-pra/index.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-23T09:33:48-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/simple-methods-and-tools-for-an-agile-law-pra/simple-methods-and-tools-for-an-agile-law-pra</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: helvetica, microsoft sans serif, arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 19px;&quot;&gt;The following post is excerpted from a talk given at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: helvetica, microsoft sans serif, arial, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 12px; line-height: 19px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stmarytx.edu/law/index.php?site=homecoming&quot; title=&quot;St. Mary's University School of Law&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;St. Mary's University 2012 Law Homecoming CLE&lt;/a&gt; on March 23, 2012.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: helvetica, microsoft sans serif, arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 19px;&quot;&gt;In the fast-moving world of software development and startup companies, Agile methodologies are used to keep companies competitive. This discussion introduces Agile concepts to the legal field and discusses how&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stmarytx.edu/law/pdf/Roach.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Slide Handouts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; you can apply&lt;/a&gt; some of these concepts to your practice.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;prezi-player&quot;&gt; 
&lt;object height=&quot;363&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://prezi.com/bin/preziloader.swf&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#ffffff&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;flashvars&quot; value=&quot;prezi_id=krxyay__5x6r&amp;amp;lock_to_path=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&amp;amp;autoplay=no&amp;amp;autohide_ctrls=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://prezi.com/bin/preziloader.swf&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; flashvars=&quot;prezi_id=krxyay__5x6r&amp;amp;lock_to_path=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&amp;amp;autoplay=no&amp;amp;autohide_ctrls=0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What's a trademark and how do I get one?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/whats-a-trademark-and-how-do-i-get-one/index.html"/>
   <updated>2011-10-14T03:34:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/whats-a-trademark-and-how-do-i-get-one/whats-a-trademark-and-how-do-i-get-one</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #ffff99; padding: 10px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This article is for educational, informational, and reference purposes only.&amp;nbsp;This article assumes that Texas and U.S. Federal Law applies.&amp;nbsp;This is not legal advice, and you should consult an attorney about trademark and other laws may apply to your specific situation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First: a bit of background:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I get from new business owners (and many established ones) is &quot;&lt;strong&gt;How can I keep someone else from using my name?&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;. &amp;nbsp;One answer is &quot;&lt;strong&gt;through trademark rights&lt;/strong&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The good news is that you may already have trademark rights to your business name, but probably not in the way you would think they arise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people assume that once they register a business (either as a DBA with a county clerk) or more formally with the Secretary of State, that they have reserved that name. &amp;nbsp;You might also think that by registering your business as a corporation or LLC that you are guaranteed that nobody else is using that name. &amp;nbsp;Unfortunately, that's not usually the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instead, trademark rights can arise simply through use of the name in the course of business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Federal (nationwide) and Texas (statewide) trademark rights can be acquired through what is called common-law use. &amp;nbsp;These use-based rights occur without any registration or formal filing, but are more limited than formal &quot;registered marks.&quot; &amp;nbsp;A trademark applies to goods (physical products) and a servicemark applies to services (together just called &quot;Marks&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's a trademark (vs a patent vs a copyright)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the U.S. Patent &amp;amp; Trademark Office (U.S.P.T.O.), a&amp;nbsp;trademark is &quot;a word, phrase, symbol, or design, or a combination thereof, that identifies and distinguishes the source of the goods of one party from those of others.&amp;nbsp;A service mark is the same as a trademark, except that it identifies and distinguishes the source of a service rather than goods.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USPTO has a good summary of basic federal registration questions &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uspto.gov/trademarks/basics/BasicFacts_with_correct_links.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Trademark Facts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;available in PDF&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I think their explanation is pretty accurate and concise: &quot;A trademark typically protects brand names and logos used on goods and services. A copyright protects an original artistic or literary work. A patent protects an invention. For example, if you invent a new kind of vacuum cleaner, you would apply for a patent to protect the invention itself. You would apply to register a trademark to protect the brand name of the vacuum cleaner. And you might register a copyright for the TV commercial that you use to market the product.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uspto.gov/trademarks/basics/BasicFacts_with_correct_links.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Trademark FAQs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BasicFacts_with_correct_links.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Law Trademarks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;trade; + ℠&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common law rights are usually indicated by the [ TM ] symbol. These rights pre-date the registration laws on both state and federal levels. &amp;nbsp;In fact, the term &quot;trademark&quot; first arose in pre-colonial Britain when bakers would stamp their loaves of bread with marks to identify which baker created the otherwise indistinguishable loaf. &amp;nbsp;Just as then, businesses today can use their mark &quot;in commerce&quot; and obtain common-law rights to the mark.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if a clothing manufactuer sews its name and/or logo into the clothing it sells, (and assuming that mark isn't already taken by someone else) then that clothing maker may have a common law trademark in those geographic areas in which it distributes its product. &amp;nbsp;A business claiming common law rights can apply the &amp;trade; symbol after its mark or ℠ after a servicemark to indicate that rights are claimed for that mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Statutory &quot;Registered Trademarks&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trademark law is somewhat unusual because it exists at both the state level and national level. In Texas, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statutes.legis.state.tx.us/&quot; title=&quot;Tex. Bus. &amp;amp; Com. Code &amp;sect;16.15&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;business and commerce code&lt;/a&gt; provides that trademarks can be registered with the Secretary of State, even if they are not federally registered marks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A mark registered with the Texas Secretary of State offers greater protection than a common-law mark, but less than a federally registered mark. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State registration (under&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statutes.legis.state.tx.us/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Tex.  Bus. &amp;amp; Com. Code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;sect;16.15)&amp;nbsp;can automatically broaden geographic protection to the entire state, whereas common-law marks are geographically limited to the locations in which business is conducted using the mark. &amp;nbsp;These days, state-level registration isn't as big of a sellling point as it once was, but can help in some situations. &amp;nbsp;For instance, a local business selling sustainable meat and produce at a farmer's market in San Antonio might want to use registration to expand its protection to avoid a future competitor in Abilene from using the mark, even if the San Antonio business only sells and markets its product out of one location at present. &amp;nbsp;But, if you're an internet-based startup selling online tools for facebook users, that might not be a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State registration can also give enforcement of trademarks &quot;more teeth&quot; (see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statutes.legis.state.tx.us/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Tex.  Bus. &amp;amp; Com. Code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;sect;16.15 and&amp;nbsp;&amp;sect;&amp;sect;16.26-.27). &amp;nbsp;These are mostly benefits you (and your lawyer) would want to have if trademark infringement problems result in litigation (or threats of litigation). &amp;nbsp;Defensively, state registration is presumed (prima facie) legal proof that your business was using the mark for your products. &amp;nbsp;Offensively, it allows for a statutory cause of action against others who might later infringe on your mark. &amp;nbsp;And, it makes counterfeitting of your mark a crime under&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statutes.legis.state.tx.us/&quot;&gt;Tex. Penal Code &amp;sect; 32.23.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But, Texas registration does not extend beyond the state, does not guarantee against other federal registrants, and doesn't permit use of the federal &amp;reg; symbol.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federal Statutory &quot;Registered Trademarks&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-large;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;reg;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A federally registered trademark is probably the best choice for businesses that plan to expand regionally, nationally, or who do business with out-of-state customers over the Internet. &lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;It's also the only proper entitlement to use of the federal &amp;reg; symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A federal registration provides each of the benefits of the state registration described above, and broadens the application of those provisions nationwide. In addition, a federal registration allows you to bring suit in Federal Court instead of state courts, allows a mark to become &quot;incontestable&quot; after a period of time, can act as a basis for foreign registrations, can allow&amp;nbsp;U.S. Customs and Border Protection to stop infringing goods at importation, and offers additional procedural safeguards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements For Registered Marks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/usc_sec_15_00001052----000-.html&quot; title=&quot;15 USC 1052 at Cornell LII&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lanham Act&lt;/a&gt; (15 U.S.C.&amp;nbsp;&amp;sect;1051 et. seq.) is the controlling statute that defines federal trademark law in the US. &amp;nbsp;In defining what &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;can&lt;/span&gt; be registered, the law &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;includes&lt;/span&gt; most marks and then &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;excludes&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;categories that are ineligible. &amp;nbsp;This is one area in which a lawyer who specializes in trademarks can often be helpful, as the statute is lengthy and its' exclusions (and cases interpreting its exclusions) are a prime reason that the USPTO rejects new registrations. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, some examples of marks that are NOT acceptable under&amp;nbsp;&amp;sect;1052 include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;merely descriptive&quot; marks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;geographically descriptive&quot; marks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;surnames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functional names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mark that would cause dilution, blurring, or tarnishment of an existing mark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disparaging,&amp;nbsp;immoral, deceptive, or scandalous marks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;certain flags or coats of arms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;depictions of living or dead inviduals without consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;How Do I Apply for Registration?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The application for federal marks is done through the USPTO. &amp;nbsp;Most applications are submitted through the TEAS (Trademark Electronic Application System) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uspto.gov/teas/teasplus.htm&quot; title=&quot;USPTO TEAS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TEAS Plus&lt;/a&gt; systems online, following the guidelines of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitlaw.com/source/tmep/#400&quot; title=&quot;Bitlaw TMEP&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TMEP (Trademark Manual of Examining Procedure)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texas state-level registrations can be done through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sos.state.tx.us/corp/trademark.shtml&quot; title=&quot;Texas SOS Direct&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Form 901&lt;/a&gt;, filed with the Texas Secretary of State. You can also register through the online &lt;a href=&quot;https://direct.sos.state.tx.us/acct/acct-login.asp&quot; title=&quot;SOS Direct&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SOS Direct&lt;/a&gt; e-filing system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Can I Do It Myself or Do I Need A Lawyer?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's kind of like fixing a car. &amp;nbsp;If you go to an average mechanic, he's might tell you it needs professional repair. &amp;nbsp;If you go to an average car dealer, he's might tell you to get a new car. &amp;nbsp;If you go to an average auto parts shop, they'll might tell you that just buying the part and doing it yourself is fine. If you go to a really good mechanic, hopefully he'll look it over and tell you when it's a simple matter, when it's not, and lay out some options. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this post is informational, not advice, it's impossible to say what would suit any particular client or particular mark. &amp;nbsp;But, here's what the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sos.state.tx.us/corp/tradefaqs.shtml#tm11&quot; title=&quot;Texas Trademark FAQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Texas Secretary of State FAQ says&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;posterous_medium_quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I have to use an attorney to apply to register a mark?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No; however, it is important to understand that although we can assist with the nuts and bolts of completing an application, our office cannot give you any legal or business advice. We initially reject an estimated 90% of applications that are submitted to us by non-attorneys. You might benefit from consulting with an attorney about the best way to protect your intellectual property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Finally, How do I make those registration symbols on my web site?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HTML symbols for copyright and registered trademarks are part of the HTML specification and are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;trade; &amp;amp;trade;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;copy; &amp;amp;copy;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;reg; &amp;amp;reg;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common-law symbols are accessed via character code as follows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;℠ &amp;amp;#8480;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;trade; &amp;amp;#153;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;copy; &amp;amp;#169;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;reg; &amp;amp;#174;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sos.state.tx.us/corp/tradefaqs.shtml&quot; title=&quot;Texas Secretary of State Trademark FAQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Texas Trademark Registration FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sos.state.tx.us/corp/trademark.shtml&quot; title=&quot;Texas Secretary of State Trademark Forms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Texas Trademark Forms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/15/usc_sup_01_15_10_22.html&quot; title=&quot;U.S. Lanham Act at Cornell LII&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lanham Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitlaw.com/source/tmep/#400&quot; title=&quot;Trademark Manual of Examining Procedure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TMEP&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Startups and New Businesses - What's in the 2010 Small Business Jobs Act?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/startups-and-new-businesses-whats-in-the-2010/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-09-27T09:24:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/startups-and-new-businesses-whats-in-the-2010/startups-and-new-businesses-whats-in-the-2010</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2010/09/23/statement-president-obama-final-passage-small-business-jobs-bill&quot; title=&quot;Obama to sign small business jobs bill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;President&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/idUSN2710251620100927&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;signed into law&lt;/a&gt; the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010 (H.R. 5297). &amp;nbsp;The House Bill came before the Senate for a vote and was passed by the Senate last week by a vote of 61 to 38. As with many legislative works, the $30 billion bill contains some valuable changes in the law, but they don't necessarily jump off the page. Proponents of the bill claim it will enable &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/idUSN2710251620100927&quot; title=&quot;Small Business Credit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$300 billion in new small business credit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/idUSN2710251620100927&quot; title=&quot;Small Business Jobs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;create 500,000 new jobs&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Large small businesses&quot; (an oxymoron, for sure) already gained from the 2009 Recovery Act stimulus, and that continues, with expansions to the SBA 7(a) and 504 loan programs. &amp;nbsp;Federal contracting rules have been overhauled, with benefits to well-connected contractors and new entrants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But many of these federal programs leave the average small business or startup wondering &quot;what's in it for me? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;The good news is, plenty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How about a ten grand ($10,000.00) deduction to offset costs of starting a new business?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New businesses started in 2010 can deduct up to $10,000.00 in startup expenses. &amp;nbsp;This is up 2x, doubling the 2009 deduction of $5,000.00. &amp;nbsp;As most founders can attest, the process of starting a business can result in all sorts of unexpected costs and expenses. &amp;nbsp;This grab-bag deduction can seriously help defray startup expenses in the first year. &amp;nbsp;Of course, you need to be on a path to revenue and income, or a tax deduction becomes less useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purchasing equipment for your trade or business? Get a first-year write-off for up to $500,000.00 and a phased incentive up to $2 million.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This applies to IRS Code &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/businesses/small/article/0,,id=213666,00.html&quot; title=&quot;IRS Section 179 Expenses&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Section 179 &lt;/a&gt;expenses, which were already benefitted by ARRA, the 2009 American Recovery and Reinvestment Act. This includes purchases of machinery and equipment, livestock, presses, office equipment, store counters, cases, and other non-structural build-out items. &amp;nbsp;This also includes non-custom computer software and manufacturing equipment. &amp;nbsp;However, you'll need to act quickly, as some of the limits revert back at the end of 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey, your cell phone is now easier to deduct.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While cell phone deductions probably don't top your list of big-ticket expenses, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/publications/p946/ch05.html&quot; title=&quot;Cell Phone Listed Property Amendment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a minor procedural change&lt;/a&gt; removes them from a category of expense that was previously somewhat difficult to deduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your health insurance can be deductible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A self-employed business can deduct a family health plan premium for the 2010 tax year. &amp;nbsp;Whether this will be extended or made permanent isn't entirely clear, but I hope that this provision will continue in future years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a bad year? If you have current losses and prior profitable years, you might be able to get a refund on prior tax payments. Apply your tax credits over five years and against the AMT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have current losses, but paid tax on profitable years anytime in the last five years, you can potentially get an immediate refund of some of those payments. &amp;nbsp;Businesses with gross receipts under $50 million (and that's most small businesses and startups) can &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2009/11/05/news/economy/tax_breaks_for_business/index.htm&quot; title=&quot;CNN tax breaks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;carry back their general business credits&lt;/a&gt; to offset up to five years of tax liabilities and can apply those credits to the AMT (alternative minimum tax). Prior to the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010, you could only carry back credits for one year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issuing stock? Get a 100% capital gains exclusion for up to $10 million.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is a bit trickier, as not all small businesses will qualify. &amp;nbsp;Likewise, the issuance of stock must occur in the pretty narrow window between the bill's passage in late September and the end of 2010. &amp;nbsp;That said for those who qualify, the bill increases the capital gains exclusion to 100% on stock issues that meet requirements and fall within the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lending Stimulus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to dive too deep into this one, but as with prior stimulus, this bill includes a wide variety of lending changes designed to make capital flow more readily to small businesses. &amp;nbsp;You can read all about it at the White House &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2010/09/27/president-obama-signs-small-business-jobs-act-learn-whats-it&quot; title=&quot;White House&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;press release page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources to Learn More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.senate.gov/legislation/download/?id=6ab1714d-3bd5-43f4-8096-177cbcbb8cd2&quot; title=&quot;Senate Summary HR 5297&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Senate Summary&lt;/a&gt; of the Act (PDF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.senate.gov/legislation/download/?id=603e4898-e487-4770-8c68-4610469a589f&quot; title=&quot;Legislative Text Small Business Jobs Act&quot;&gt;Full Legislative Text&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.senate.gov/legislation/download/?id=ad57e59b-53a9-4f72-89a4-e757a1a66af5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amendments&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.senate.gov/legislation/details/?id=da799068-5056-a032-5229-92cebbd2b7a0&quot;&gt;Additional Legislative History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, the obligatory legalese:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: liberation-serif-1, liberation-serif-2, serif; font-size: 12px; color: #444444; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;The typical disclaimers apply: This post is provided as general information, and is not intended as legal advice. &amp;nbsp;The applicability of this information will vary based upon countless variables unique to your business, and the legality and applicability of this information will vary depending upon your jurisdiction. &amp;nbsp;You should always consult a professional, such as your attorney, accountant, or tax advisor before making decisions. IRS CIRCULAR 230 DISCLOSURE: While this information is not considered legal advice, any tax-related information contained in this communication (including any attachments or links) is not intended or written to be used, and cannot be used, by any taxpayer for the purpose of (1) avoiding tax-related penalties under the U.S. Internal Revenue Code or (2) promoting, marketing or recommending to another party any tax-related matters addressed herein.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bilski v. Kappos Opinion Issued by Supreme Court</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/bilski-v-kappos-opinion-issued-by-supreme-cou/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-28T06:08:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/bilski-v-kappos-opinion-issued-by-supreme-cou/bilski-v-kappos-opinion-issued-by-supreme-cou</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Jun 28, 2010&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bilski v. Kappos (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patentlyo.com/patent/2010/06/bilski-v-kappos-business-methods-out-software-still-patentable.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;via Patently-O&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although Bilski's claims were held unpatentably abstract, the Supreme Court has re-affirmed that the door to patent eligibility should remain broad and open.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Today, the Court once again declines to impose limitations on the Patent Act that are inconsistent with the Act’s text. The patent application here can be rejected under our precedents on the unpatentability of abstract ideas. The Court, therefore, need not define further what constitutes a patentable “process,” beyond pointing to the definition of that term provided in §100(b) and looking to the guideposts in &lt;em&gt;Benson&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Flook&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Diehr&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By refusing to state any particular rule or categorical exclusion, the Court has almost certainly pushed Section 101 patent eligibility to the background in most patent prosecution and litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&quot;http://patentlyo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Patently-O &lt;/a&gt;has a great writeup on the highly anticipated Bilski opinion.  You can read the Supreme Court's full opinion &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/09pdf/08-964.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Supreme Court Bilski Opinion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  There's also a short, but relatively unhelpful,mention in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703964104575334780441176648.html?mod=WSJ_hpp_LEFTTopStories&quot; title=&quot;WSJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the amici and commentators had high hopes for this opinion to provide clarity and (in some cases) a major shift in what was considered patentable subject matter.  Instead, the High Court took a more conservative approach and in essence said that the existing law was sufficient to decide Bilski's method claims without new law.  There's another post on Patently-O that pre-dated the issuance of the opinion that seems to pretty much &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patentlyo.com/patent/2010/06/bilski-kenny-rogers-and-supreme-court-rule-46.html&quot;&gt;call the outcome accurately&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the opinion came as something of a disappointment to those who felt that there was a wide gap between the holdings in &lt;em&gt;Benson&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Flook&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Diehr, &lt;/em&gt;the latter two in particular. I wouldn't be surprised if this issue re-emerges again in the form of legislative action on the underlying patent statutes, given that the Court's opinion provided so little guidance.  It's unlikely that the opinion is going to satisfy the calls for patent reform from companies and individuals seeking to narrow the scope of patentability and reduce the availability of software patents in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress has a full slate going into an election season, so I'd be surprised to see much action on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2010/06/21/technology/patent_reform/index.htm&quot;&gt;Patent Reform Act of 2010&lt;/a&gt;.  This perennial legislation is oft-proposed, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patentlyo.com/patent/2010/03/patent-reform-act-of-2010-an-overview.html&quot;&gt;seldom acted upon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>IRS Publishes Guidance on Business Health Care Tax Credit - small businesses get up to 35% back </title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/irs-publishes-guidance-on-business-health-car/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-17T06:50:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/irs-publishes-guidance-on-business-health-car/irs-publishes-guidance-on-business-health-car</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sba.gov&quot; title=&quot;SBA.gov&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SBA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/news/2010-05-17/tax-credit-to-pay-third-of-small-business-health-cost-update1-.html&quot; title=&quot;Small Business Administration Quote&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;half of the small businesses between three and 10 people don’t provide health care&lt;/a&gt;, but would like to offer it.  According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.treasury.gov&quot; title=&quot;Treasury.gov&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;US Treasury&lt;/a&gt;, the Affordable Care Act contains provisions that would allow up to a 35% tax credit for qualifying businesses, who may receive both state and federal tax credits. Fortunately, determining whether your business qualifies for those credits just became much easier.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, you should consult your attorney or tax advisor for advice tailored to your situation.  However, the government has made it easier to determine where your business falls thanks to new guidance issued by the IRS and the US Treasury Department.  On May 17, 2010, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.treasury.gov/press/releases/tg698.htm&quot; title=&quot;US Treasury TG-698&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Treasury issued release TG-698&lt;/a&gt;, which outlines some common scenarios.  The IRS has issued a more in-depth publication via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/n-10-44.pdf&quot; title=&quot;IRS Notice 2010-44&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IRS Notice 2010-44 (pdf).&lt;/a&gt; Here are some of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Getting Money For Health Care: Combined Credits up to 75%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you're a business in Texas, the 35% credit is a welcome step, allowing for federal credits where no direct credits were previously available.  In other states that do provide direct assistance, the combined federal-state credits can cover &lt;em&gt;up to 75% of an employer's premium costs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Federal Tax Credits&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A common adage is that &quot;the devil is in the details,&quot; and that's often true with the transition between legislative action and implementation.  However, based upon the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/viewer?url=http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/n-10-44.pdf&quot; title=&quot;IRS Guidance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent guidance&lt;/a&gt;, the new Act's provisions look like they'll be implemented generously. Beginning immediately in 2010, businesses may be able to claim up to a 35% tax credit for health care premiums.  Starting in 2014, that number &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/9PtUGR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;increases to a 50%&lt;/a&gt; federal credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Health Insurance Coverage&quot; is defined broadly.  In addition to the traditional medical insurance, the Section 45(R) credit includes dental, vision, and other limited-scope coverage.  There is an explicit allowance in the IRS Notice for long-term care, home nursing care, disease-specific riders like cancer coverage, &quot;or any combination thereof&quot;.  There are some restrictions, such as requiring a minimum 50% employer contribution, and each must be a stand-alone qualifying arrangement, but your tax advisor, insurance agent, or legal counsel should be able to help you determine whether your current offering qualifies and what changes or tweaks may be needed to ensure compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Tax Incentives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Act does not reduce federal credits based on state benefits, unless the combination would exceed the employer's contribution. State tax incentives are monetary incentives usually provided by tax credits or deductions that reduce your businesses' tax bill. The National Conference of State Legislatures (NCSL) provides a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncsl.org/?tabid=13956&quot; title=&quot;NCSL Employer Tax Incentives&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;summary of Employer Health Coverage Tax Incentives&lt;/a&gt; for businesses in Alabama, Arizona, Colorado, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Kentucky, Maine, Montana, Michigan, Missouri, North Carolina, Oklahoma, South Carolina, Utah, and Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State Premium Assistance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Premium assistance is money available for direct or indirect payment or reduction of premiums. Unlike tax-driven incentives, premium assistance can be un-bundled from the tax system and potentially provides another avenue to defray costs for tax-disadvantaged businesses. The NCSL maintains a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncsl.org/?tabid=14526&quot; title=&quot;NCSL Premium Assistance List&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;list of premium assistance programs&lt;/a&gt; for businesses in Arkansas, Idaho, Kentucky, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Montana, New Mexico, Oklahoma, Washington, and Tennessee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health Savings Accounts (HSAs) allow for tax-free accounts that are usually coupled with high-deductible insurance that provide an alternative to traditional premium-only insurance. The NCSL also provides a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncsl.org/Default.aspx?TabId=14462&quot; title=&quot;NCSL HSA programs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;list of health savings account (HSA)&lt;/a&gt; programs that interested businesses should review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Employer and Plan Eligibility Requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tax credits are often referred to as &quot;Small Business Health Care Credits&quot;.  But who is a small business?  Fortunately, the IRS guidance allows for some flexibility in this definition. In order to be an eligible small employer, &quot;(1) the employer must have fewer than 25 full-time equivalent employees (FTEs) for the taxable year; (2) the average annual wages of its employees for the year must be less than $50,000 per FTE; and (3) the employer must maintain a “qualifying arrangement.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/viewer?url=http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/n-10-44.pdf&quot; title=&quot;IRS Notice&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;--IRS Notice, SII(A)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &quot;qualifying arrangement&quot; is one where the employer pays at least 50% of the per-employee premium on a uniform percentage.  There are some caveats for 2010 due to the implementation phase-in, so if you plan to claim a 2010 credit, be sure to ask your advisor about the 2010 rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the IRS guidance, employers can elect for the most favorable method of determining FTE hours (full time equivalent).  This is important for eligibility because the tax credit is highest for employers with 10 or fewer FTE employees. Benefits extend up to 25 FTE employees, and the employer is able to choose whether to look to actual hours of service, or can use estimated hours based on total days or weeks of service.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calculation is basically a five-step approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the employees who are taken into account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the number of hours of service performed by those employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculate the number of the employer’s FTEs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the average annual wages paid per FTE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the premiums paid by the employer for a qualifying arrangement under section 45(R)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-drop/n-10-44.pdf&quot; title=&quot;IRS Notice 2010-44&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;full IRS Notice 2010-44&lt;/a&gt; contains all of the details, as well as example scenarios for common business situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Some Cautionary Notes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any law, the actual legislation isn't without caveats.  For example, while the tax credit is scheduled to increase to 50% in 2014, the credit is only available for six years total, unless amended. Businesses can claim the credit in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/9PtUGR&quot; title=&quot;US Treasury (via bitly)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tax years 2010 to 2013, and for two additional years&lt;/a&gt; thereafter. Based on these numbers, the plan is expected to save small businesses &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/9PtUGR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;up to $40 billion&lt;/a&gt; through 2019.  The flip side of that is that the government will lose the same amount in tax revenue, if not made up by other sources. Also, lawmakers were also worried about so-called &quot;Cadillac Plans&quot; and therefore, the eligible contribution is&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/9PtUGR&quot; title=&quot;US Treasury (via bitly)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;capped based on the average cost&lt;/a&gt; of health insurance in your state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I've mentioned, the typical disclaimers apply: This post is provided as general information, and is not intended as legal advice.  The applicability of this information will vary based upon countless variables unique to your business, and the legality and applicability of this information will vary depending upon your jurisdiction.  You should always consult a professional, such as your attorney, accountant, or tax advisor before making decisions. IRS CIRCULAR 230 DISCLOSURE: While this information is not considered legal advice, any tax-related information contained in this communication (including any attachments or links) is not intended or written to be used, and cannot be used, by any taxpayer for the purpose of (1) avoiding tax-related penalties under the U.S. Internal Revenue Code or (2) promoting, marketing or recommending to another party any tax-related matters addressed herein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Is The iPad A Threat To E-Readers Like Amazon's Kindle?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/is-the-ipad-a-threat-to-e-readers-like-amazon/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-06T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/is-the-ipad-a-threat-to-e-readers-like-amazon/is-the-ipad-a-threat-to-e-readers-like-amazon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;IPad's Versatility Threatens to Sideline E-Readers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;By &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/apr2010/tc20100412_516320.htm#&quot;&gt;Olga Kharif&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;Internet retailer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;.com ... may need to write a new chapter for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; in the face of fierce competition from Apple's iPad ...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt; analysts have said the iPad would likely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=conewsstory&amp;amp;tkr=HPQ%3AUS&amp;amp;sid=aJlnuEWpJJJs&quot;&gt;take a bite out of sales of dedicated e-book readers&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;'s popular &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; ... Wall Street analysts are already slicing their forecasts for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; sales.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;Charlie Wolf, a senior analyst ... cut his forecast for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; sales this year, settling on [2.5 million units, down from 3.6 million]. &quot;It's not a compelling product,&quot; he says of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; , because Apple's iPad offers more features, such as the ability to play video, plus a more compelling design ...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;consumers dumping &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;s for iPads&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;To keep pace with consumers' heightened expectations ... Susan Kevorkian, an analyst at market researcher IDC, says &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; needs to update the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; with a color screen and replace its buttons with touchscreen capabilities. &quot;They absolutely need a color screen—the sooner the better,&quot; she says ...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/apr2010/tc20100412_516320.htm&quot;&gt;businessweek.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/technology/content/apr2010/tc20100412_516320.htm&quot; title=&quot;Buisnessweek Article&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;above linked article&lt;/a&gt; proposes that the iPad has so changed the playing field that the Kindle&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; is &quot;not a compelling product&quot;.  But, this view is too narrow-minded in its outlook and thus misses out on the true Kindle&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;-iPad issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;its not about the hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; isn't really a piece of e-book reading hardware.  It's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;a platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;.  I don't have access to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2F&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;'s sales data, but I'd surmise that the iPad has actually increased sales of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Kindle Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;, not decreased them.  Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; customers can &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;&gt;buy&lt;/span&gt; rent Kindle Books through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;desktop Kindle reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;iPhone Kindle reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;, the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;hardware Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; devices, and now the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;iPad Kindle reader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has done what they do well - attack the top of the market.  But just as the iMac didn't do away with generic PCs, the iPad isn't going to dispose of dedicated e-Readers.  The iPhone still hasn't supplanted media-rich mobile phones except among consumers willing and able to pay the &quot;Apple Tax&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kindle&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; hardware simply needs to evolve to better reach those people who won't shell out for Apple-premium products.  I never owned a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T963C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0015T963C&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0015T963C&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; hardware reader, and probably never will.  But I did install the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Ffeature.html%3Fie%3DUTF8%26ref_%3Damb%5Flink%5F352814002%5F3%26docId%3D1000493771&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Kindle app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; on my iPad and iPhone.  Thus, Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; has gained a customer where they wouldn't have previously were it not for the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;'s big-picture challenge is going to be keeping their software ahead of the curve and preserving a better reading experience than iBooks.  Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; can also win on price/licensing if they choose.  Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;'s MP3 store and iTunes both sell music, but Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;'s offering tends to be priced better and have greater compatibility than iTunes tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big threat that remains is not Apple's hardware, but their contracts.  Today's antitrust laws may be written in a way that fails to address the anti-competitive powers of App Stores and EULAs, but that's a topic for another day. Were Apple to decide to kick Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; off their platform as they&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2010/04/08/adobe-flash-apple-sdk/&quot; title=&quot;Apple Gives Adobe The Finger&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; recently did with Adobe's Flash&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2010/05/04/wsj-confirms-apple-under-preliminary-antitrust-investigation-ove/&quot; title=&quot;Apple Antitrust Investigation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; will face a more significant problem&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 12px; color: #444444; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmp.ly/5&quot; style=&quot;color: #106896; text-decoration: underline; padding: 0px; margin: 0px;&quot;&gt;http://cmp.ly/5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Document Production and Review Tips using Adobe Acrobat Pro</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/document-production-and-review-tips-using-ado/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-04T04:19:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/document-production-and-review-tips-using-ado/document-production-and-review-tips-using-ado</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to run multiple Acrobat OCR batches at once:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;I was about to dive into a document review project today and ran into some &quot;technical challenges&quot;. Here's how it worked out.  Hopefully this will save others some time in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Situation&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: normal;&quot;&gt;Today's another one of those days ... my morning started out in a room stacked full of boxes of documents that were produced to us.  Now, I need to make sense out of these and find those proverbial needles in the haystack.  Fortunately, the tedious scanning process was already done for me, and I had PDF copies of the production on discs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Goal&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;The immediate goal is to go through the documents and look for key words and phrases, with a more in-depth review guided by a roadmap that is developed today. The quickest way to do this is to make the documents searchable. Often, you can get a scanning service provider (or your own scanner/copier) to perform OCR text recognition during the scanning process.  In this case, we received the documents as un-processed PDFs, so the recognition had to be done in-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Problem -- Speed&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Today's desktop computers often have plenty of horsepower.  This particular job was run on a dual-core &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002QQ8CC4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002QQ8CC4&quot;&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B002QQ8CC4&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; desktop with 4GB of RAM.  However, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0018QV3OC?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0018QV3OC&quot;&gt;Adobe Acrobat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0018QV3OC&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; is single-threaded for OCR.  What that means is, you can tell it to batch process multiple documents, but it goes through them sequentially, one at a time.  When you have thousands, or hundreds of thousands of documents, this poses a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started the batch as normal, by going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0018QY9WA?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0018QY9WA&quot;&gt;Adobe Acrobat Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0018QY9WA&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;'s &quot;Document&quot; menu and selecting &quot;Recognize text in multiple files using OCR ...&quot;.  I added the files from our Windows (SMB) file share and set it to work.  After a few hundred pages, it was clear that this approach wasn't going to be finished in any reasonable amount of time.  What I needed was &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;concurrency&lt;/span&gt;.  From my processor usage graph, I could tell that my computer had plenty of spare cycles, but that Acrobat just wasn't using them effectively.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Solution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One approach that I've used in the past is simply to split up the job across several different computers. This is fine if you have enough computers, but it's still inefficient and ties up several machines in the office with each one running at less than peak speed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Step 1:&lt;/span&gt; More Acrobat!&lt;br /&gt;This time, I took a different approach.  I made a copy of the Acrobat application in the Finder.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Screen_shot_2010-05-04_at_10.43.22_AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Document Production and Review Tips using Adobe Acrobat Pro&quot; /&gt;Each copy will consume about 900mb of disk space, but on a modern system this isn't a problem.  Acrobat's license allows for multiple backup copies on a single computer, so up to this point you're OK on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/products/eulas/&quot; title=&quot;Adobe End User License Agreement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;licensing&lt;/a&gt;.  I gave each one a slightly different icon so that I could tell them apart when active.&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Screen_shot_2010-05-04_at_10.43.25_AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Document Production and Review Tips using Adobe Acrobat Pro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Step 2:&lt;/span&gt; Queue up Jobs.&lt;br /&gt;Now, you can launch each copy of Acrobat separately and add documents to each one's queue independently.  However, to do this right, you'll need a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/products/eulas/pdfs/Gen_WWCombined-20080205_1329.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Acrobat License&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt; for each concurrent copy of Acrobat.  I reviewed their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/products/eulas/pdfs/Gen_WWCombined-20080205_1329.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Acrobat License&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;retail license&lt;/a&gt; and it looks like they define &quot;the Software&quot; in such a way that it's licensed per copy, not per computer.  The backup copy provision probably doesn't cover concurrent usage. In my case, I had two retail copies of Acrobat as well as another copy that was bundled in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fs%3Fie%3DUTF8%26x%3D0%26ref_%3Dnb%5Fsb%5Fss%5Fc%5F1%5F20%26y%3D0%26field-keywords%3Dadobe%2520creative%2520suite%25205%26url%3Dsearch-alias%253Dsoftware%26sprefix%3Dadobe%2520creative%2520suite&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&quot;&gt;Adobe Creative Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; package. If you have a site license or other agreement with Adobe, your licensing may be different. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Step 3:&lt;/span&gt; Doubled Productivity (or more).&lt;br /&gt;Most desktop computers these days are dual-core systems or better.  On the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002QQ8CC4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002QQ8CC4&quot;&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B002QQ8CC4&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;, running two copies of Acrobat is the most efficient, with each one loading up a different processor core.  If you had a high-end machine with 8 cores, (and 8 copies of Acrobat) you could linearly scale up the workload. Another advantage to running multiple copies is that you can get work done in one copy while another copy runs the batch processing.  If you're on a Mac, you can also use the bult-in Preview.app program to read and review PDF files while your Acrobat is running OCR jobs.  Sadly, Preview.app doesn't do OCR on its own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Screen_shot_2010-05-04_at_10.42.45_AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Document Production and Review Tips using Adobe Acrobat Pro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Take-Away&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Running multiple Acrobat jobs on one computer beats tying up several different systems at once. However, licensing issues can be a pain if you want to run a large number of concurrent jobs.  For full-time production, I'd stick with a copy provider or hardware scanner that provides OCR.  You can also get standalone software like &lt;a href=&quot;http://abbyyusa.com/&quot; title=&quot;ABBYY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ABBYY&lt;/a&gt; FineReader that specializes in OCR.  For small jobs, even &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlesystem.blogspot.com/2009/09/google-docs-ocr.html&quot; title=&quot;Google Docs OCR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Docs can now OCR&lt;/a&gt; documents.  When it comes down to it, these kind of work-arounds shouldn't be necessary.  Acrobat is a &quot;professional&quot; product (it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0018QY9WA?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0018QY9WA&quot;&gt;says so on the box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=nathanroachco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0018QY9WA&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt; !) It's inexcusable that Acrobat Pro doesn't run batch jobs like this in parallel.  At a minimum, it could parallelize page recognition, even if it attacked documents sequentially.  But, until Adobe does a bit more to modernize its Acrobat product line, a bit of creativity and an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/products/eulas/&quot; title=&quot;Adobe Licensing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;additional tithe&lt;/a&gt; to Adobe can still get the job done quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A final caveat:&lt;/em&gt; As part of this process, I discovered that Acrobat also has a propensity to crash when it tries to save batch-processed documents to a network SMB server.  So, be sure to save to the local disk then copy back to your file server when done.  Reading directly from the server doesn't seem to be an issue. Finally, I'm trying out Amazon's program, so some of the links in this post are affiliate links - &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmp.ly/5&quot;&gt;http://cmp.ly/5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Clean Up Your Writing - Tips for Lawyers to Improve Motions and Memos</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/clean-up-your-writing-tips-for-lawyers-to-imp/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-20T03:04:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/clean-up-your-writing-tips-for-lawyers-to-imp/clean-up-your-writing-tips-for-lawyers-to-imp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While some lawyers ply their trade primarily in the courtroom, the reality is that most of us spend the majority of our time on written work product, not eloquent jury arguments.  This week, I came across two links that are quick reads and have the potential to markedly improve work product with little time invested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typographyforlawyers.com/&quot; title=&quot;Typography for Lawyers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typography For Lawyers&lt;/a&gt;. The site is run by Matthew Butterick, an attorney in Los Angeles. His pre-law background is graphic design and typography, with experience running a website development studio.  I also came from a non-law (and web programming/design) background and thus the attention to presentation that he's advocating really resonated with me.  I spent several years helping attorneys gain maximum impact in the courtroom by applying good presentation skills to their in-trial advocacy.  Mr. Butterick makes the point that those same principles can apply to your written work as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;When you speak to a judge, do you stand at the lectern, eyes cast downward, and read from a script in a monotone? No, of course not. To maintain the judge’s attention during your argument, you change the speed and volume of your delivery; you gesture; you extemporize. You do this because you don’t merely want to be &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt;—you want to &lt;em&gt;persuade&lt;/em&gt;. The text matters, but so does the presentation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;So it is on the printed page. The text matters, but if that’s all that mattered, then everything could be set in 12-point Times New Roman. And that would be the equivalent of staring at the lectern.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typography is always important because presentation is always important&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second resource I'd like to point out today is an article entitled &lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/5520058/4-danger-signs-to-search-for-before-sending-off-your-novel&quot;&gt;4 Danger Signs To Search For, Before Sending Off Your Novel&lt;/a&gt; by Charlie Jane Anders.  The tips from that article may be geared to fiction writers, but they apply also to legal writing. A few quick word searches through your pleadings for these warning signs can improve the final product with a minimal time investment. I highly recommend hitting the link to read the full article, but the TLDR version of what to watch out for is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Adverbs.&lt;/strong&gt; In a nutshell, you do a search for &quot;ly&quot; in your manuscript. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Sentences beginning with &quot;It.&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; The main problem with &quot;it&quot; is that it's a pronoun, so you must be absolutely clear about what &quot;it&quot; refers to. And when a sentence begins with &quot;it,&quot; that can be another red flag pointing to bad writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) There was, or there were. &lt;/strong&gt;Most people will tell you to keep your use of the verb &quot;to be&quot; to an absolute minimum. But you can't avoid using &quot;is&quot; or &quot;was&quot; altogether, and like everything else, &quot;to be&quot; has its place in your prose ... But you absolutely should do a quick search for &quot;there was&quot; and &quot;there were&quot; — which are pretty clearcut instances of the verb &quot;to be&quot; flopping around when a stronger verb could be flexing its muscles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Was being, or were being.&lt;/strong&gt; Just as most experts will tell you to avoid the verb &quot;to be&quot; as much as possible, they'll also warn you away from passive verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Cambria, Georgia, Times New Roman, Calibri, serif;&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm frequently a passive voice offender in my early drafts and in casual writing. Therefore, I religiously scrub my writing for passive voice whenever I have the time.  With the four suggestions above, I can add a few checkboxes to my quick-search routine.  Maybe one day I'll even have the discipline to apply those to my blog posts =D.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Use of Harmonic Functions in Computer Animation at Pixar (article at AMS)</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/use-of-harmonic-functions-in-computer-animati/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-16T03:20:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/use-of-harmonic-functions-in-computer-animati/use-of-harmonic-functions-in-computer-animati</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I came across this article published at the American Mathematical Society as part of my morning reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.ams.org/samplings/feature-column/fcarc-harmonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www1.ams.org/featurecolumn/images/march2010/remy.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moving Remy in Harmony: Pixar's Use of Harmonic Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a really interesting discussion of how various geometric formulae are used to enable the characters to move in a natural way.  I think exposing this kind of real-world application of relatively easy-to-understand concepts is a great way for educators to show their students how seemingly austere concepts can be made to do &quot;fun&quot; things that apply to their own lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animation shops that lead their field today draw upon the talents of artists, mathematicians, programmers, and many other disciplines to tell a compelling story.  The viewer gets to look through the mind's eye of the storyteller, but only because countless professionals have plied their trade to make it all work seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, next time you wonder that &quot;tan&quot; or &quot;cos&quot; key on your calculator is for, just think of talking mice ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: xx-small; color: #999999;&quot;&gt;[Fair Use Statement:  The image of Remy from Pixar Studios' Ratatouille may be a copyright of Disney/Pixar and used, if at all, herein  for nonprofit educational purposes, and is an insubstantial portion of the work as a whole that does not significantly impact the value or market of the original work.  Any images displayed in this post are links to a third party source and are not hosted or supplied by the author. ]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple's Presentation Mastery - Why time stands still at 9:42 on iPhone</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/apples-presentation-mastery-why-time-stands-s/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-08T09:41:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/apples-presentation-mastery-why-time-stands-s/apples-presentation-mastery-why-time-stands-s</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpwwwnetworkw_wFeCg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple's Presentation Mastery - Why time stands still at 9:42 on iPhone&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.networkworld.com/community/node/59824&quot;&gt;networkworld.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network World writers wondered why &quot;every picture of every iPhone in every Apple ad shows the time as 9:42.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, the answer is based upon the timing of the Keynote presentations.  An Apple VP explained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Monaco, Courier;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&quot;We design the (product launch) keynotes so that the big reveal of the product happens around 40 minutes into the presentation. When the big image of the product appears on screen, we want the time shown to be close to the actual time on the audience's watches. But we know we won't hit 40 minutes exactly.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&quot;So you add a couple of minutes?&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&quot;Yeah! And for the iPhone, we made it 42 minutes. It turned out we were pretty accurate with that estimate, so for the iPad, we made it 41 minutes. And there you are - the secret of the magic time.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wanted evidence that Steve Jobs and co. are truly the masters of public presentation, it doesn't get much stronger than this.  Attorneys, sales reps, and many other professions require presentations to juries, clients, or the public at large.  But how often do you run across a presenter who bothers to make sure that embedded images in the presentation are actually keyed to the projected time that the image will be discussed on screen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only are these guys anticipating the time their screenshots will appear on screen, they're actually honing their timing down to the minute and correcting based on analysis of prior presentations.  Perhaps that borders on obsessive-complusive behavior, but it shows that they really sweat the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you this prepared for your next oral argument?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What To Do When A Hard Drive Fails | Server Zone</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/what-to-do-when-a-hard-drive-fails-server-zon/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-06T02:37:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/what-to-do-when-a-hard-drive-fails-server-zon/what-to-do-when-a-hard-drive-fails-server-zon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpserverdzone_rdoaj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;What To Do When A Hard Drive Fails | Server Zone&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://server.dzone.com/news/what-do-when-hard-drive-fails&quot;&gt;server.dzone.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post linked above walks you through steps to recover data from a hard drive by repeatedly freezing it. &amp;nbsp;I haven't tried it, nor do I plan to. The best option, of course, is to have a backup so you don't need to resort to extreme measures to recover your data.  Hard drives are cheap these days, and both Windows and Mac have built-in backup tools such as Time Machine.  They're cheap insurance to make sure you don't wind up needing to freeze hard drives or perform voodoo rituals to get your data back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing drive makers don't tell you is that as drive sizes increase (and density per platter increases), the statistical probability of a single-bit error on any given volume increases.  So, as drives get bigger, the probability of failure increases unless additional steps (such as rigorous backup or error-correction) are taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An update on my Clear.com service, and the LTE / WiMAX conundrum</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/an-update-on-my-clearcom-service-and-the-lte/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-27T07:25:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/an-update-on-my-clearcom-service-and-the-lte/an-update-on-my-clearcom-service-and-the-lte</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;http://nathanroach.com/im-trying-clearcom-clearwire-4g-wimax-interne&quot;&gt;wrote about Clear&lt;/a&gt; when it was first launched in San Antonio. &amp;nbsp;The TLDR version of that article is that I had mixed feelings about the service from a business perspective, but felt that the technology was promising. &amp;nbsp;I've been using Clear's service now for almost four months, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nathanroach.com/im-trying-clearcom-clearwire-4g-wimax-interne&quot;&gt;that article&lt;/a&gt; has gotten some decent traffic and &lt;a href=&quot;http://everydaysimplicity.blogspot.com/2010/03/clear-wireless-4g-internet-service-is.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cross-links&lt;/a&gt;, so another update is due. &amp;nbsp;Here are the big changes since I last looked at them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;The pricing &quot;for life&quot; pitch is gone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This was probably just a promo deal, but when the service launched, you could get mobile for $30/mo and home+mobile for about 50-60/mo &quot;for life&quot;. The home+mobile is really just two lines of service. &amp;nbsp;There's no reason you couldn't have both lines acting as mobile. The current two-line plan adds a teaser rate, but drops the guaranteed pricing: &quot;Pay only $30/month for the 1st two months, then $55/month thereafter.&quot; The single-line plan is even cheaper up front but winds up being more expensive long-term: &quot;Pay only $15/month for the 1st two months, then $40/month thereafter.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;They may be capping speeds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also looks like there *might* be speed caps now. &amp;nbsp;The old plan offered unlimited download &lt;em&gt;speeds, &lt;/em&gt;which I read as meaning that the actual download speed of your connection was limited only by the WiMAX protocol's limits and that bandwidth that's provisioned to the towers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mobile plan advertises &quot;unlimited internet usage&quot; and &quot;download speeds up to 6.0 Mbps&quot;. &amp;nbsp;In reality, I never saw more than 6 megs down on the unlimited plan, but there is a difference between unlimited usage with a &quot;speed limit&quot; of 6.0 Mbps and uncapped, unlimited usage. &amp;nbsp;I can't tell if this was actually implemented as a technological &quot;hard cap&quot; or whether it's just a more accurate re-wording of their legalese. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;You can get contract-free pricing if you're careful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get to the sign-up link, you can choose a 2-year Agreement or Month-to-Month. &amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;DO NOT CHOOSE THE AGREEMENT.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The only benefit to the agreement is that you can add the equipment as a monthly leased expense. WIth month-to-month you have to pay for the equipment up front. &amp;nbsp;Still, the cost of leasing equipment almost never works out in the customer's favor. &amp;nbsp;Ever since the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uiowa.edu/~cyberlaw/FCCOps/1968/13F2-420.html&quot;&gt;Carterfone&lt;/a&gt; decision, operators have been prohibited from requiring only their own&amp;nbsp;equipment&amp;nbsp;on telephone networks, and while I don't know if Clear's internet-only offering would be covered, it's a safe bet that you should pick up your own gear if you can. After all, y&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20060915/162903.shtml&quot;&gt;ou don't want to wind up paying $4,900 for use of rotary phone, do you?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Besides, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.ebay.com/?_from=R40&amp;amp;_trksid=p3907.m38.l1313&amp;amp;_nkw=clear+usb+modem&amp;amp;_sacat=See-All-Categories&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;get 4G USB adapters on Ebay&lt;/a&gt; for $10-$15. &amp;nbsp;Why pay monthly for cheap hardware?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;You can get Clear service from your Cable Co.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear has agreements with Sprint, Time Warner, and Comcast. &amp;nbsp;These guys are just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phonenews.com/time-warner-to-resell-wimax-as-road-runner-mobile-on-december-1st-9269/&quot;&gt;re-branding the Clear service&lt;/a&gt;, and selling it at a markup. &amp;nbsp;Time Warner calls theirs &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://text.broadbandreports.com/shownews/Time-Warner-Cable-Launches-Roadrunner-Mobile-105765&quot;&gt;Road Runner Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. I know Sprint holds an interest in Clear, and it's possible that TW and Comcast do as well. &amp;nbsp;Unless you prefer the convenience of consolidated billing, or just love cable company customer service, you can probably save some money buying directly from Clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;LTE is coming, 4G+ is here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With technology, there's always the &quot;next greatest thing&quot; right around the corner. &amp;nbsp;Heck, WiMAX deployments are still relatively cutting edge. &amp;nbsp;AT&amp;amp;T is still pushing 3G on the iPhones and iPad. (article on this to follow). &amp;nbsp;But, LTE is another kind of 4G technology that could offer a 2x to 10x improvement over WiMAX, depending upon how the carriers deploy it. &amp;nbsp;Verizon is pre-announcing&amp;nbsp;LTE gear already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, Clear has implemented plans they're calling 4G+ that can fall back to 3G (on Sprint's EVDO network), but with limitations on speed and total transfer. &amp;nbsp;There's probably enough for a separate post just on LTE and WiMAX, and&amp;nbsp;Clear has made some public statements about possibly moving to LTE when it's more broadly available. &amp;nbsp;So, this could get interesting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Would I recommend it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear's service isn't flawless. &amp;nbsp;But it's good enough that I've switched to it full-time at home and keep a mobile USB adapter in my laptop bag. &amp;nbsp;I just called Time Warner and scheduled a disconnect. &amp;nbsp;Between free over-the-air HDTV and Clear's wireless internet, I can cut the cord. &amp;nbsp;If you're a speed junkie, you'll still get faster speeds on a wired cable modem. &amp;nbsp;If you use VOIP extensively and aren't in a strong coverage area, calls on Clear's network can be choppy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm happy enough with it to run Clear as my only ISP. &amp;nbsp;But I'm also tolerant of bleeding-edge technology glitches and can troubleshoot most problems myself. &amp;nbsp;I think Clear is mostly there in terms of being ready for mainstream adoption. &amp;nbsp;As long as they can keep enough bandwidth to the towers and they don't over-subscribe users, I think they'll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Programmers are a commodity… Experts are Not.</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/programmers-are-a-commodity-experts-are-not/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-19T08:16:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/programmers-are-a-commodity-experts-are-not/programmers-are-a-commodity-experts-are-not</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across the following blog post earlier today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A month or so ago I noticed a quite odd advertise on the billboard just outside &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kth.se/abe/inst/philhist/tekhist?l=en_UK&quot;&gt;the department I&amp;rsquo;m working at KTH&lt;/a&gt;, going more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CodeRay&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;C++ junior programmer wanted!
SQL, Javascript and Actionscript a plus
Call 0123 for more info&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Eventually the listing changed to]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CodeRay&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Offering internship!
Do you have any experience with HTML/web site building?
Call 0123 if you're interested!&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow developers, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we all start to charge &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://usingimho.wordpress.com/2010/03/19/programmers-are-a-commodity-right/&quot;&gt;usingimho.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author of that blog post is missing the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programmers&lt;/em&gt; are a commodity. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lawyers&lt;/em&gt; are a commodity. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Managers&lt;/em&gt; are a commodity. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dentists&lt;/em&gt; are a commodity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Experts are not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any given field, probably 80% of the practitioners can do an adequate job and at least complete the tasks required by their position.  In my experience, that number narrows to about 40% if the requirement is that the job is performed on time, on budget, and performed correctly the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, less than 20% of the practitioners are going to be &quot;standouts&quot;.  And only about 5% will be experts.  Getting to the standout stage can be a function of talent, luck, or experience.  Reaching the expert stage typically requires all three: talent/intelligence + luck/opportunity + experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts can justify a premium rate because they deliver premium results.  Turning back to the programmer's comment, not every project or every task requires an expert.  And experts are only made through experience.  So as long as the hiring manager is up front about whether the task requires expert-level skill, I see no problem with providing an opportunity for a less skilled worker to gain experience if the project is of an ordinary nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, you see these same trends in many professions.  Most employees are fungible.  But if given time to develop experience, the experts will distinguish themselves.  After that point, the question for the employer is simply whether the task at hand requires a &quot;cog&quot; or an expert.  Most businesses require both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What is ACTA and why should you care?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/what-is-acta-and-why-should-you-care/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-15T10:23:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/what-is-acta-and-why-should-you-care/what-is-acta-and-why-should-you-care</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Brief:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The really short version is that ACTA is a treaty that involves copyrights and global intellectual property protections. &amp;nbsp;More specifically, it's a series of proposals that are being negotiated on an international level with the goal of writing treaty language that each country can pass that will become law in the signatory nation upon its passage.
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Sounds thrilling, right?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Big Picture:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;But this is big-deal stuff and here's why: in the United States, &lt;em&gt;treaties are considered the law of the land under the U.S. Constitution. &lt;/em&gt;Moreover, negotiation of treaties is a &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://caselaw.lp.findlaw.com/DATA/CONSTITUTION/ARTICLE02/10.html&quot;&gt;presidential monopoly&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&amp;nbsp;Just like an ordinary contract, the details are hammered out in negotiations between the signatories long before a presidential pen signs the treaty. &amp;nbsp;This is the phase where the &quot;meat&quot; of the treaty is decided. &amp;nbsp;After it's been signed, congress is only involved through ratification. &amp;nbsp;&quot;[The executive branch] alone negotiates. Into the field of negotiation, the Senate cannot intrude; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findlaw.com/scripts/getcase.pl?navby=case&amp;amp;court=us&amp;amp;vol=299&amp;amp;invol=304#319&quot;&gt;Congress itself is powerless to invade it&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. &amp;nbsp;What that means is that treaties can be enacted, and U.S. citizens can be constrained based upon negotiations that take place between the President and the heads of state for other nations. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Normally, when laws are passed in Congress, the public has the ability to comment, lobby, and become involved in the process. &amp;nbsp;It doesn't always work, but on big-ticket items, people have a chance to at least voice their concerns to their representatives before a bill is passed. &amp;nbsp;An example is the pending health-care bill. &amp;nbsp;Whether you're for it or against it, the issue has been debated in public and voters can hold their representatives accountable if a bill is passed that doesn't &amp;nbsp;reflect the majority of voters is any given congressional district.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's on the Nutritional Label:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;There's an old adage that &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Talk:Otto_von_Bismarck&quot;&gt;laws are like sausages&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- it's better not to seem them being made&quot;. Unfortunately, ACTA doesn't come with a nutritional label. &amp;nbsp;In fact, it's deeply shrouded in secrecy. &amp;nbsp;But here is what we know:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;1. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Third-Party (Intermediary) Liability.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;This would basically set out a default rule that you don't have to be a direct copyright infringer to be on the hook for liability. &amp;nbsp;The most common example is an internet service provider. &amp;nbsp;Let's say your Mom/wife/sister posts a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20070725/224422.shtml&quot;&gt;video of a baby dancing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;to music on the radio, and uploads it to YouTube. &amp;nbsp;Not only could she get sued by Prince or the recording industry for violating the copyright (actually, the performance rights), but the &lt;em&gt;intermediary&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;could also be sued under an intermediary liability regime. &amp;nbsp;That means YouTube, their upstream providers, your home internet provider, and anyone else in the &quot;path&quot; of the infringement could get sued. &amp;nbsp;That's a great thing for copyright holders. &amp;nbsp;The chance of collecting much money from your Mom isn't great, but being able to bring in some &quot;deep pockets&quot; can make the litigation much more profitable.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;2. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Limited &quot;Safe Harbor&quot; for ISPs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Intermediary liability is a big problem for tech companies if it's implemented without checks. &amp;nbsp;Safe Harbor allows the intermediary third party to avoid liability under specific circumstances. &amp;nbsp;In the U.S., the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Millennium_Copyright_Act&quot;&gt;Digital Millennium Copyright Act&amp;nbsp;(DMCA)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the controlling law, and the safe harbor provisions are implemented by&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_Copyright_Infringement_Liability_Limitation_Act&quot;&gt; take-down and notice provisions&lt;/a&gt;. While the take-down and notice system has drawn significant criticism, it is what US citizens have become accustomed to.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;At present, most copyright complaints result in a letter to the poster's ISP or the file's online host, and the alleged infringement is taken offline unless or until the poster presents a counter-notice showing that the poster has the proper rights to use or post the content. &quot;If the leak reports are correct, this would no longer be true. Instead, IS&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2009/11/leaked-acta-internet-provisions-three-strikes-and-&quot;&gt;Ps would be required to automatically terminate a&amp;nbsp;customer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;upon a rightsholder's repeat allegation of copyright infringement at a particular IP address.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;This would be a significant change for bloggers and internet users. &amp;nbsp;Rather than having a single image or video taken down upon a complaint of infringement, your ISP would be either able or required to turn off the spigot of your internet access. &amp;nbsp;In effect, a single complaint (without judicial process) could stifle a person's online access and speech proactively. &amp;nbsp;There are also proposals to make this a &quot;three strikes&quot; approach that would require more than one allegation of infringement. &amp;nbsp;In practice, however, most of the copyright complaints that I've seen allege more than a single infringement. &amp;nbsp;None of the three strikes proposals that I've seen would require a judicial finding of infringement prior to termination, which reduces the three strikes to little more than a formality. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;3. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Criminal Sanctions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As well, ACTA signatories will be required to adopt both civil and criminal legal sanctions for copyright owners' technological protection measures. &amp;nbsp;That means things like unlocking cell phones, copying DVDs, or removing digital watermarks could be criminalized on a global level. &amp;nbsp;Most reasoned observers would agree that copyright holders need to have a way to stop unauthorized copying. &amp;nbsp;The &quot;DVD pirate&quot; who buys a DVD at Wal-Mart and sells 1,000 copies for $5 a pop out of the back of a van should be held properly accountable. &amp;nbsp;But do you really want the FBI breaking down your front door when your child loads a &quot;cracked&quot; video game on his online-connected Xbox? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Importance of Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;ACTA raises a large number of issues that concern internet-connected citizens. &amp;nbsp;For example, some have interpreted ACTA to require that &quot;ISPs have to proactively police copyright on user-contributed material. This means that it will be impossible to run a service&amp;nbsp;like Flickr or YouTube or Blogger, since hiring enough lawyers to ensure that the mountain of material uploaded every second&amp;nbsp;isn't infringing will exceed any hope of profitability&quot;. Or what if we wind up with &quot;Mandatory prohibitions on breaking DRM, even if doing so for a lawful purpose (e.g., to make a work available to disabled people;&amp;nbsp;for archival preservation; because you own the copyrighted work that is locked up with DRM)&quot;? (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2009/11/03/secret-copyright-tre.html&quot;&gt;Corey Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As mentioned above, there is no open process required for treaty negotiation. &amp;nbsp;In fact, the negotiations are often done in secret. &amp;nbsp;The&amp;nbsp;Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement (ACTA) is being negotiated for the United States by the United States Trade Representative (USTR). &amp;nbsp;The USTR is an executive-branch diplomat that reports the President. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/remarks-president-export-import-banks-annual-conference&quot;&gt;President Obama, in recent remarks&lt;/a&gt;, has said that &quot;We have to rebuild our economy on a new, stronger, more balanced foundation for the future &amp;ndash;- a foundation that will advance the American people&amp;rsquo;s prosperity at home,&amp;nbsp;and support American leadership in the world.&quot; That sounds good to me, right?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As Obama said in the speech &quot;The fact is other countries haven&amp;rsquo;t always played by the same set of rules. &amp;nbsp;America hasn&amp;rsquo;t always enforced our trade rights, or made sure that the benefits of trade are&amp;nbsp;broadly shared. &amp;nbsp;And we haven&amp;rsquo;t always done enough to help our workers adapt to a changing world.&lt;/div&gt;
Now, there&amp;rsquo;s no question that as we compete in the global marketplace, we&amp;rsquo;ve got to look out for our workers. &amp;nbsp;But to look out for our workers, we&amp;rsquo;ve got to be able to&amp;nbsp;compete in the global marketplace. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s never been as important an opportunity for America as it is right now.&quot; I don't think you'll find many Americans who would disagree with these goals. &amp;nbsp;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;But, at some point, the rubber meets the road. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/remarks-president-export-import-banks-annual-conference&quot;&gt;Sayeth Obama&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;What&amp;rsquo;s more, we&amp;rsquo;re going to aggressively protect our intellectual property. &amp;nbsp;Our single greatest asset is the innovation and the ingenuity and creativity of the American&amp;nbsp;people. &amp;nbsp;It is essential to our prosperity and it will only become more so in this century. &amp;nbsp;But it&amp;rsquo;s only a competitive advantage if our companies know that someone else&amp;nbsp;can&amp;rsquo;t just steal that idea and duplicate it with cheaper inputs and labor. &amp;nbsp;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with other people using our technologies, we welcome it &amp;ndash;- we just want to&amp;nbsp;make sure that it&amp;rsquo;s licensed, and that American businesses are getting paid appropriately. &amp;nbsp;That&amp;rsquo;s why USTR is using the full arsenal of tools available to crack down on&amp;nbsp;practices that blatantly harm our businesses, and that includes negotiating proper protections and enforcing our existing agreements, and moving forward on new&amp;nbsp;agreements, including the proposed Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;And that brings us back to the whole treaty issue. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ustr.gov/about-us/press-office/press-releases/2009/june/ambassador-ron-kirk-announces-plan-move-forward-negot&quot;&gt;Negotiations on the ACTA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;began in June 2008. &amp;nbsp;Even though the treaty has been in negotiation for nearly two years, the Obama administration&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2009/03/were-not-releasing-acta-docs-says-us-again.ars&quot;&gt;refuses to release the secret documents&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that detail what is being proposed. &amp;nbsp;In essence, if you're Joe Citizen, the US Trade Rep doesn't think you need to know what's being negotiated. Unless, of course, you're a lobbyist - &quot;cleared&quot; lobbyists do get access. &quot;Because ACTA is intended to create new global international IP enforcement standards, including these provisions will allow US negotiators to&amp;nbsp;achieve what they have not been able to do to date &amp;ndash; ensuring that the US's overbroad implementation of the WIPO Internet Treaty TPM&amp;nbsp;obligations becomes the global standard.&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2009/11/leaked-acta-internet-provisions-three-strikes-and-&quot;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The Obama administration has been less than forthcoming. &amp;nbsp;Although the USTR has made&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ustr.gov/about-us/press-office/press-releases/2009/june/ambassador-ron-kirk-announces-plan-move-forward-negot&quot;&gt;some vaguely worded statements&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that &quot;In keeping with President Obama's transparency goals, USTR will continue its efforts to ensure that the public is well-informed about the&amp;nbsp;negotiations,&quot; very little information has been released. Instead,&lt;a href=&quot;http://onthecommons.org/content.php?id=2408&quot;&gt; it's been publicly reported that&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&quot;[i]n response to [a] FOI&amp;nbsp;request, the White House Office of the U.S. Trade Representative refused to release the&amp;nbsp;ACTA documents.&amp;nbsp;It stated&amp;nbsp;that the&amp;nbsp;information about the treaty &amp;ldquo;is properly classified in the interest of national security pursuant to Executive Order 12958.&amp;rdquo; I don't see how copyright violations, or even bootlegged DVDs rise to the level of a &quot;national security&quot; issue. &amp;nbsp;It would be even worse if the Obama administration decided to proceed with ACTA as an executive agreement. &amp;nbsp;&quot;Executive agreements do not require Congressional approval before they may take effect&quot; and,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicknowledge.org/issues/acta&quot;&gt;according to Public Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, can be used to &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicknowledge.org/issues/acta&quot;&gt;policy launder&lt;/a&gt;&quot; material that wouldn't pass as legislation through ordinary channels.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Way Forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Regardless of what the USTR advocates for, and what the signatories to the ACTA treaty finally come up with, open access for public comment should be a part of the process from the beginning. If we, as a global people, are to make decisions that will affect our daily lives on the internet, we need more than just closed negotiations to that legislation.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quickly Find The Differences in Two Photos Using Photoshop</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/quickly-find-the-differences-in-two-photos-us/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-11T04:07:11-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/quickly-find-the-differences-in-two-photos-us/quickly-find-the-differences-in-two-photos-us</id>
   <content type="html">Recently, ScanCafe ran a promotion offering up to 35% off their service. But, there was a catch ... &quot;We made some changes to the photograph of Lange. Can you find all five? For each one you find, we'll take 5% off.&quot; The photos they provided were the following:&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DorotheaLange_600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quickly Find The Differences in Two Photos Using Photoshop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You *could* just look at the photos, maybe blow them up a bit, and figure out manually what changes they made. I spotted three immediately. But, I prefer to know rather than guess. So, I decided to quickly drop the images into Adobe Photoshop to confirm my guesses. The steps are as follows: &lt;p /&gt; 1) Open the images in Photoshop CS4. &lt;p /&gt; 2) Separate them into individual layers. (Select the 2nd image, right-click, and choose &quot;Layer via Cut&quot;). &lt;p /&gt; 3) Align the two layers so that they are on top of one another. (I did this by making the top layer 50% opaque, and sliding it over until there was no ghosting. This is similar to onion-skinning. Then, I changed the opacity back to 100%).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Screen_shot_2010-03-11_at_11.2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quickly Find The Differences in Two Photos Using Photoshop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4) Now change the layer blending method to &quot;Difference&quot;. You'll get a mostly black image with white or grey highlights where differences exist. As a caution, if images contain a lot of JPEG compression noise, or if a large amount of sharpening was used, those will show up as differences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Screen_shot_2010-03-11_at_11.3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quickly Find The Differences in Two Photos Using Photoshop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5) Identify the differences. Here, there are four that stand out right away. First is the alteration to woman, now holding a camera. Second is the deletion of the windshield wiper that's present in the first photo. Third, is the (subtle) change to the license plate's digits. Fourth is the modification of the tree line on the ridge, extending its length in the second frame. That's one that I hadn't spotted without Photoshop's help. In looking for #5, you might be misled by the back door of the wagon. Yes, there's been an alteration there, but that probably comes as a result of sharpening, given that the pixel differences are only on the edges of the back door and wheel. It's also possible that they were shifted a few pixels or so, but I don't think that's what the contest is looking for. My guess for number five is the scratch in the right center of the first frame ahead of the vehicle's bumper. That doesn't stand out strongly in the difference analysis, but it does appear more noticeably if you switch the layer order and re-apply the difference blending. That makes my count Five, plus sharpening artifacts. &lt;p /&gt; So, that's it! Two minutes in photoshop and I feel much more confident about my answers ! &lt;p /&gt; [Disclaimer-ish Note: In case you were wondering, ScanCafe seems to have taken the original image from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Lange_car.jpg&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Lange_car.jpg&lt;/a&gt; or from a government source, therefore reproduction would be permissible as a public domain work created by a US Government employee during the course of the person's official duties. The modified image by ScanCafe (and my changes in this post) are derivative works, insufficiently different enough from the original to be regarded as a new work. I'm certainly not going to be trying to register my chicken-scratch red circles a new work ...]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I'm tough on web browsers ...</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/im-tough-on-web-browsers/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-01T09:01:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/im-tough-on-web-browsers/im-tough-on-web-browsers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is sort of an aside from my usual content, but I thought it was worth sharing because I firmly believe that the web browser is going to take up an increasing share of our computing tasks over the next few years. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I ask a lot from my computers, and I'm particularly tough on web browsers. &amp;nbsp;As you can see from the screenshot, my Safari &lt;em&gt;web browser is taking up 1.01 Gigabytes of memory. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;And, it has almost 2 gigs of virtual memory allocated. &amp;nbsp;It's also using over 100% of my CPU, which is possible in this case because I have more than one processor core. &amp;nbsp;As you can see, it's all browser utilization, as Flash (oft demonized by Apple) is only using 6% CPU and about 80 megs of RAM. &amp;nbsp;In Safari's defense, I have just shy of 100 tabs open at this point, many running javascript-heavy sites. &amp;nbsp;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I need to try out Chrome and Firefox with these kind of loads and see if they fare better. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Screen_shot_2010-03-01_at_4.40.png&quot; alt=&quot;I'm tough on web browsers ...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;I downloaded the latest version of Chrome for Mac, and made it my default browser for a day. &amp;nbsp;The result is that after transferring all my open tabs from Safari (which was using 768M at the time), Chrome is only using 99.8M of resident memory for the same number of tabs. &amp;nbsp;Even Firefox is using more than that, and it only has three tabs open at the moment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I'll probably continue to use Firefox as my &quot;work&quot; browser, because it renders the legal research websites that I use with greater fidelity than the webkit based browsers. &amp;nbsp;But for my personal browsing, I think I'll leave Chrome as the default. &amp;nbsp;I'm going to miss Safari's thumbnail preview window, which looks nicer and holds more locations than Chrome's equivalent. &amp;nbsp;But that's a small trade-off for a memory footprint that is much much lower.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Silent Rotor Blade Is High-Tech ... or is it?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/a-silent-rotor-blade-is-high-tech-or-is-it/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-01T02:27:48-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/a-silent-rotor-blade-is-high-tech-or-is-it/a-silent-rotor-blade-is-high-tech-or-is-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpwwwpopscico_CBplc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Silent Rotor Blade Is High-Tech ... or is it?&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsci.com/technology/article/2010-02/video-eurocopter-introduces-silent-rotor-blade-stealth-choppers&quot;&gt;popsci.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This new helicopter blade is supposed to reduce the noise produced by the rotor, and the linked article has some interesting computer data to back it up. But, It looks very similar to the wing configuration of a hawk or other predatory bird.  Given that hawks and owls often dive their prey at high speed, reducing the noise produced by their approach increases their success rate.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not surprised that CFD shows that function follows a form that's existed in nature for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Attorneys Are More Popular Than Lawyers</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/attorneys-are-more-popular-than-lawyers/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-02-11T03:55:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/attorneys-are-more-popular-than-lawyers/attorneys-are-more-popular-than-lawyers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The word &quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;&gt;attorney&lt;/span&gt;&quot; is searched for in Google with nearly three times the frequency of the term &quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;&gt;lawyer&lt;/span&gt;&quot;, at least within the United States. I would have expected expected the inverse, based upon the frequency with which I hear those terms mentioned in casual conversation. This is good data if you're a practitioner engaged in marketing your services. Call yourself an attorney, not a lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/viz.png&quot; alt=&quot;Attorneys Are More Popular Than Lawyers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chart was generated by Google, comparing the relative traffic of the word &lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;&gt;attorney (red)&lt;/span&gt; vs. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;&gt;lawyer (blue)&lt;/span&gt;. The upper graph indicates that among actual searches, the attorney term is much more popular. it also appears to have a relatively steady demand. Attorney has more volatility than lawyer, and both exhibit some interesting temporal shifts. For example, both terms drop in popularity near the end of each year. Perhaps the holiday spirit cuts down on people's desire to initiate litigation, or people just stay out of trouble around Christmas, who knows! &lt;p /&gt; When you look at the lower graph, there's not as much of a spread between the terms, as used by the news media. My hypothesis is that when people need representation, they search for an attorney. When the news is reporting on someone's bad behavior or about attorneys in general, the word lawyer is used as a pejorative. You hear a lot more lawyer jokes than attorney jokes. There also seems to be an increase in both by the media, and it doesn't seem to correlate strongly with economic indicators such as stock market performance. Simply put, although the demand for attorneys in the general population is more or less static, the media seems to pay increasing attention to our profession. Make of that what you will.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Law Practice - Don't Let the Urgent Drive Out The Important</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/on-law-practice-dont-let-the-urgent-drive-out/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-31T09:46:32-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/on-law-practice-dont-let-the-urgent-drive-out/on-law-practice-dont-let-the-urgent-drive-out</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;I recently read an interview with Henry Kissinger and it reminded me of the practice of law. &amp;nbsp;Former Secretary of State Kissinger was discussing the challenges that come with being Secretary of State or National Security Advisor. &amp;nbsp;In talking about the decisions he made, he remarked -- &quot;at the end of every day you almost have to make a decision - whom are you going to insult by not dealing with his or her problems?&quot; &amp;nbsp;While not all jobs are 24/7 triage, it's all too common a problem. &amp;nbsp;According to Kissinger, &quot;one of the problems of government is to separate the urgent from the important, and make sure you're dealing with the important and &lt;b&gt;don't let the urgent drive out the important&lt;/b&gt;.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;That same comment could apply to running a law practice. For every client, their problem is the most important one - and from their perspective it should be. &amp;nbsp;The tricky part is, of course, actually making it work. That's a management skill many people don't have but those that do tend to have the most successful firms and the happiest clients. &amp;nbsp;Some people are able to do this instinctively, but I tend to believe that the really effective practitioners give it conscious thought and have developed a system that works within the unique constraints of their practice. &amp;nbsp;How do you&amp;nbsp;avoid letting the urgent drive out the important?&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick Thoughts & Caveats on the Apple iPad</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/quick-thoughts-caveats-on-the-apple-ipad/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-27T06:14:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/quick-thoughts-caveats-on-the-apple-ipad/quick-thoughts-caveats-on-the-apple-ipad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's going to be a lot of buzz surrounding the new Apple iPad announced by Steve Jobs today. &amp;nbsp;I won't rehash all the news that's already on the blogosphere, but I did want to point out a few caveats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the 3G model if you want location serv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ices&lt;/strong&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Yes, it'll cost at least $629 instead of $499 for the base model. &amp;nbsp;But you need the 3G SIM card to get GPS. &amp;nbsp;Otherwise, you get the same wifi-based location services that the 2G iPhone used. &amp;nbsp;Given how many apps these days are location-aware, the extra money is worth it to have the GPS hardware on-board. &amp;nbsp;Also, I wouldn't be surprised to see an announcement this summer for an iPhone 4G and a iPad 4G. &amp;nbsp;Assuming AT&amp;amp;T can handle the data demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple crippled the video-out. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It will play HD 720p video on the internal screen. &amp;nbsp;But the video out port is analog-only. &amp;nbsp;Which means VGA to a computer or Standard Def 576p to a TV. Blech. &amp;nbsp;Maybe an AppleTV refresh is coming based on this thing's video engine, but the iPad isn't an HDTV convergence device yet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They could have called it the iPod Touch DX&lt;/strong&gt; instead of iPad. &amp;nbsp;Steve Jobs may call it &quot;magical&quot;, but its not revolutionary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iBooks app looks a whole lot like Delicious Library. &amp;nbsp;And it's recycling a name from Apple's consumer portable. &amp;nbsp;I wonder how many of these are going to be sold on ebay by mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It ships in 60 days. &amp;nbsp;Good luck getting one. &amp;nbsp;While I'm not blown away, I'll be in line for one anyway. It looks useful as a color Kindle or upscaled iPod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Free Online Research Tools for Lawyers</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/free-online-research-tools-for-lawyers/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-26T09:36:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/free-online-research-tools-for-lawyers/free-online-research-tools-for-lawyers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Legal Research Tools Online&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked (via Twitter) about online research tools for attorneys. &amp;nbsp;I've been using free alternatives to Lexis Nexis and Westlaw for quite a while, and decided to compile some of the best sites in a post. &amp;nbsp;It's certainly easier than trying to fit all the links in 140 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, the past has been dominated by the two big players:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lexis-Nexis (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexis.com/research)&quot;&gt;http://www.lexis.com/research)&lt;/a&gt;, from Reed Elsevier; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westlaw (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westlaw.com&quot;&gt;http://www.westlaw.com&lt;/a&gt;), from Thomson Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Why There Is A Demand For Alternatives&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons that solo practitioners, new lawyers, and even firm associates might want to use alternative services. &amp;nbsp;The first concern I often hear is the price. &amp;nbsp;With both of the big two services, you get what you pay for, and all-you-can-eat plans are out of reach for everyone except the largest firms. &amp;nbsp;In the past, I've used both services and continue to use Lexis on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second common concern is compatibility. &amp;nbsp;At the office, I have a Mac and a PC on my desk, and at home I have everything from SGIs, Linux, and BSD to Win95. Of those platforms, only the PC is 100% functional with both of the big two services, and then only if I stick with a mainline browser. &amp;nbsp;If you try to hit the commercial sites from Safari, Opera, Google Chrome, or other browsers, you can expect some pain. &amp;nbsp;I've found that Firefox on the Mac and IE on the PC are the best shots for getting everything to work smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third complaint is the interfaces. &amp;nbsp;Neither Westlaw or Lexis appear to have been designed with a set of core UX principles. &amp;nbsp;There are lots of legacy compatibility reasons why the workflow in these services has evolved in the manner that it has, but very few web apps outside the legal research arena would require hours of training to use. &amp;nbsp;But step into a law school law library and you'll see schedules for incessant training (read: indoctrination) for each package. &amp;nbsp;Having been through the training, I do appreciate the depth you get from these services as a power-user but I can't say that either is intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there's the simple fact that each is paywalled. &amp;nbsp;You need to log in, and even with cookies and session-saving, you're bound to get logged out after a period of time. &amp;nbsp;Which means that when you just want a quick answer, you have to pass through the login (and sometimes a lengthy search) process in order to proceed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free Online Tools I Found Useful As An Attorney&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Cornell Legal Information Institute&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/&quot;&gt;http://www.law.cornell.edu/&lt;/a&gt; ):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Number One on my list is Cornell's LII site. &amp;nbsp;It's very fast, and contains a wealth of resources on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/federal/&quot;&gt;Federal Law&lt;/a&gt;, the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/rules&quot;&gt; Federal Rules&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr&quot;&gt;Code of Federal Regulations&lt;/a&gt; (CFR), the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode&quot;&gt;U.S. Code&lt;/a&gt; (USC), and many-many other U.S. Federal law resources. &amp;nbsp;This includes the Constitution, commentary, the U.C.C., Uniform and Model Laws, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/&quot;&gt;and the list goes on.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;They also have topical sections, blogs, and other content. &amp;nbsp;It goes without saying that if you find Cornell's efforts to be useful, you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/donors/&quot;&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;The Texas Legislature Online&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/&quot;&gt;http://www.legis.state.tx.us/&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/em&gt;: Okay, not everyone practices law in Texas. &amp;nbsp;But if you do, the TLO web site has a comprehensive list of Texas Statutes, Senate Journals, House Journals, and the Texas Constitution. &amp;nbsp;This site is great for both Code access as well as legislative history research. &amp;nbsp;Honorable mention also goes to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.courts.state.tx.us/&quot;&gt;Texas Courts Online &lt;/a&gt;website for access to cases, oral argument, and local rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Cornell LII's State Information Page:&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.law.cornell.edu/states/listing.html&quot;&gt;http://www.law.cornell.edu/states/listing.html&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/em&gt;: Yes, this is a double-mention for Cornell, but no matter what state you're in, they have a good list of links to state-specific judicial and legislative resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;The Internet Archive&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archive.org&quot;&gt;http://www.archive.org&lt;/a&gt; ):&lt;/em&gt; The Archive is a 501(c)(3) non-profit that acts as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archive.org/search.php?query=subject%3A%22public.resource.org%22%20AND%20subject%3A%22public%20safety%20code%22%20AND%20mediatype%3Atexts&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt; for web sites, media, and public information. I've used their &quot;Wayback Machine&quot; to obtain discovery, and they recently entered into a venture with the Center for Information Technology Policy at Princeton to make available &quot;crowd-sourced&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pacer.psc.uscourts.gov/&quot;&gt;PACER&lt;/a&gt; documents via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recapthelaw.org/&quot;&gt;RECAP plugin for Firefox&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;If that sounds like a lot of technical mumbo-jumbo, the short version is that it makes public access for court electronic records truly free. That includes pleadings, motions, orders, and opinions from most Federal Courts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Resource.org&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://resource.org/&quot;&gt;http://resource.org/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;): This site is also a non-profit and they work closely with both the Internet Archive and Princeton to make public documents and court records widely available. &amp;nbsp;The bulk.resource.org site has machine-readable access to huge volumes of public documents, and the various sub-sites contain gems like &lt;a href=&quot;http://resource.org/house.gov/index.html&quot;&gt;streaming media access to the House of Representatives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Google Scholar &lt;/span&gt;( &lt;a href=&quot;http://scholar.google.com&quot;&gt;http://scholar.google.com&lt;/a&gt; ):&lt;/em&gt; Google's scholar resource has long been available as a tool for searching scientific and scholarly publications. &amp;nbsp;Recently, they added &lt;a href=&quot;http://scholar.google.com/schhp?hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=2002&quot;&gt;legal documents&lt;/a&gt; to their search, and as a result, you can now find many court cases simply by entering the name or citation. &amp;nbsp;Prior to Google Scholar's update, finding accurate pinpoint cites via web search was a risky proposition. &amp;nbsp;Google isn't perfect, and it is something of a meta-search, often linking to some of the resources I've already mentioned. &amp;nbsp;So, they lose points for originality, but gain them for accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;The Federal Register &lt;/span&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/browse/collection.action?collectionCode=FR&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;link&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;: &quot;Published by the Office of the Federal Register, National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), the Federal Register is the official daily publication for rules, proposed rules, and notices of Federal agencies and organizations, as well as executive orders and other presidential documents&quot;. &amp;nbsp;As a bonus, the Federal Register can also be accessed and downloaded via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gpo.gov:80/fdsys/bulkdata/FR&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Texas Supreme Court Webasts&lt;/span&gt;: (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stmarytx.edu/law/index.php?site=supremeCourtWebcasts&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/em&gt; I worked on this project at St. Mary's University School of Law and it's an interesting way to see the Texas Court &quot;in person&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Oyez.org:&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oyez.org&quot;&gt;http://www.oyez.org&lt;/a&gt; ): &lt;/em&gt;Oyez was enabled through a grant from the National Science Foundation, and tracks the cases and developments of the U.S. Supreme Court. &amp;nbsp;I've found their MP3 Podcasts of Supreme Court oral arguments to be very entertaining (for a law geek) and informative. They also have case summaries, transcripts, and other multimedia materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Google Patents&lt;/span&gt; ( &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/patents&quot;&gt;http://www.google.com/patents&lt;/a&gt; ): &lt;/em&gt;Although patent law is a somewhat narrow field, Google has done great work in making this practice area accessible to non-practitioners. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may have left some resources out, but this list forms my &quot;top 10&quot; in terms of frequency of use, ease of access, and overall value added for attorneys looking to replace or supplement Westlaw and Lexis. &amp;nbsp;Both attorneys and non lawyers should be able to find information on these sites that are viable free legal research tools. &amp;nbsp;I hope this helps, and I welcome comments, suggestions, or additions &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/txtechiplaw&quot;&gt;via my Twitter account.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated: Fixed some broken links. &amp;nbsp;Seems Posterous doesn't properly auto-link URLs in parentheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google CEO bails on China bluff?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/google-ceo-bails-on-china-bluff/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-21T09:23:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/google-ceo-bails-on-china-bluff/google-ceo-bails-on-china-bluff</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CodeRay&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(SAN FRANCISCO (Dow Jones)--Google Inc. (GOOG) Chief Executive Eric Schmidt said his company remains &quot;quite committed&quot; to remaining in China, but will in a &quot;reasonably short time&quot; make changes to its now-censored search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We wish to remain in China. We like the Chinese people and our Chinese employees. We like the business opportunities there and we'd like to do that on somewhat different terms than we have, but we remain quite committed to being there,&quot; he said on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schmidt said the company was &quot;in conversation&quot; with government authorities and that Google's business in China today remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We continue to follow their laws, we continue to offer censored results, but at a reasonably short time from now we will be making some changes there,&quot; he said during a conference call with analysts after the Mountain View, Calif.-based company reported better-than-expected fourth-quarter results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;CodeRay&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/BT-CO-20100121-717467.html?mod=WSJ_latestheadlines&quot;&gt;online.wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks increasingly like the Google threat to pull out of China or stop censoring results was nothing more than a bluff: one they were destined to lose.  The Chinese government isn't known for caving to public opinion or threats that don't have a very big stick in the background.  Frankly, it seems naive for Google to think it could change that stance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Google will &quot;continue to follow their laws&quot; and &quot;continue to offer censored results&quot;, that seems like a whole like folding when your bluff is called.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to Google's line in the sand?  In a &quot;reasonably short time from now&quot; they will &quot;be making some changes there&quot;.  That's a loophole wide enough to swallow the great wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google: changing the menu on the cafeteria wall isn't the same as making good on your threat &quot;to shut down Google.cn, and potentially our offices in China&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Obama:  USPTO systems are outdated.  (is this news to anyone?)</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/obama-uspto-systems-are-outdated-is-this-news/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-15T05:52:18-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/obama-uspto-systems-are-outdated-is-this-news/obama-uspto-systems-are-outdated-is-this-news</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama told technology executives today just how behind the times the government is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Believe it or not, in our patent office -- now, this is embarrassing -- this is an institution responsible for protecting and promoting innovation -- our patent office receives more than 80 percent of patent applications electronically, then manually prints them out, scans them, and enters them into an outdated case management system,&quot; Obama said a today's Forum on Modernizing Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is one of the reasons why the average processing time for a patent is roughly three years.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

				&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehill.com/blogs/hillicon-valley/technology/76055-obama-patent-offices-system-is-embarrassing?sms_ss=posterous&quot;&gt;thehill.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

While I'm not the least bit surprised by this admission, I have to think that at least certain aspects (electronic -&amp;gt; print -&amp;gt; scan) do seem ripe for automation.  Even if you'd need to take all the examiners offline while implementing the system, the net gain in time seems like it would offset the lost of productivity during the transition.  The trick is to find a way to budget for overhauls such that long term gains aren't hamstrung by a large up front capex.  Some things just can't be done gradually.
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Is the Valleywag $100,000 Apple Tablet Bounty Legal?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/is-the-valleywag-100000-apple-tablet-bounty-l/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-13T08:22:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/is-the-valleywag-100000-apple-tablet-bounty-l/is-the-valleywag-100000-apple-tablet-bounty-l</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macrumors.com/2010/01/13/valleywag-offers-questionably-legal-100000-apple-tablet-bounty/&quot;&gt;this is interesting.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://valleywag.gawker.com/5447390/announcing-valleywags-apple-tablet-scavenger-hunt-win-up-to-100000&quot;&gt;Valleywag&lt;/a&gt; announced that it is offering a bounty of up to $100,000 for information on the Apple tablet/iSlate/iTablet/ReallyBigiPhone  device.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.macrumors.com/article/2010/01/13/155036-valleywag_tablet_scavenger_hunt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;TechCrunch (and others) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/01/13/AR2010011303072.html&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that doing so might expose them to a tortious interference claim.  It's certainly a colorable argument, and it wouldn't be the first time that a big company &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.justia.com/cases/federal/district-courts/arizona/azdce/2:2006cv02555/322017/10/&quot;&gt;bullied&lt;/a&gt; a smaller one with that &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.justia.com/cases/federal/district-courts/arizona/azdce/2:2006cv02555/322017/10/&quot;&gt;cause of action&lt;/a&gt;.  It should be interesting to see how it plays out if Valleywag has any success with its campaign.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: &amp;nbsp;Well the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5448255/&quot;&gt;cease-and-desist letter &lt;/a&gt;didn't take long.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google China Hack Demonstrates the "Law of Unintended Consequences" even if Google doesn't exit China.</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/google-china-hack-demonstrates-the-law-of-uni/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-13T05:56:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/google-china-hack-demonstrates-the-law-of-uni/google-china-hack-demonstrates-the-law-of-uni</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some of Google's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itworldcanada.com/news/google-attack-part-of-widespread-spying-effort/139742&quot; title=&quot;Gmail systems were hacked&quot;&gt;Gmail systems were hacked&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;by what are believed to be Chinese intruders. &amp;nbsp;Whether the hackers were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.state.gov/secretary/rm/2010/01/135105.htm&quot; title=&quot;state sponsored&quot;&gt;state sponsored&lt;/a&gt; or not remains to be determined, but the very presence of an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.state.gov/secretary/rm/2010/01/135105.htm&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; by Secretary of State Clinton lends credibility to that possibility. &amp;nbsp;Aside from the questions that this breach raises about cloud computing in general, the exact nature of what was stolen is even more interesting. &amp;nbsp;Normally, I avoid opining in public on matters that might be considered political, but the technical details of this attack are fascinating enough that I thought it was worth adding to the public discussion on this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ironic part of this attack is that &lt;em&gt;Google may have been under surveillance by the hackers through back-doors built in to allow US surveillance in the first place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on preliminary reports, it appears that the data the hackers were able to obtain was actually &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata&quot; title=&quot;metadata&quot;&gt;metadata&lt;/a&gt; about the emails. &amp;nbsp;This might include subject line, dates, times, and recipients, but not the actual contents of the email. &amp;nbsp;The reason this data, and not the email contents, was vulnerable is in part because of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USA_PATRIOT_Act&quot; title=&quot;patriot act&quot;&gt;US anti-terrorism laws&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pen_register&quot; title=&quot;pen register&quot;&gt;pen register search&lt;/a&gt; can access&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: sans-serif, Helvetica, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;routing, addressing, or signaling information transmitted by an instrument or facility from which an electronic communication is transmitted and equivalent information used to identify internet traffic.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: sans-serif, Helvetica, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;&quot;&gt;How would someone get access to this kind of pen register data? &amp;nbsp;Most likely by accessing tools built-in by Google to allow surveillance of Google records by US law enforcement! According to some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macworld.co.uk/digitallifestyle/news/index.cfm?newsid=28293&quot; title=&quot;macworld&quot;&gt;published reports,&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 18px; color: #333333;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&quot;malware is accessing the internal intercept [systems].'&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000; font-family: sans-serif, Helvetica, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cato-at-liberty.org/2010/01/13/surveillance-secruity-and-the-google-breach/&quot; title=&quot;cato institute&quot;&gt;security experts&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial, sans-serif; line-height: 18px; color: #333333;&quot;&gt;As the volume of requests from law enforcement at all levels grows, the compliance burdens on telcoms grow also&amp;mdash;making it increasingly tempting to create automated portals to permit access to user information with minimal human intervention.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, it appears that our own surveillance systems were turned against us. &amp;nbsp;Prior to this breach, some information requests had been directed at Yahoo!, Verizon, and other major internet carriers, seeking to discover the extent of the automated data tracking systems. &amp;nbsp;The companies opposed these requests, saying that telling the public would &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2009/12/wiretap-prices/&quot; title=&quot;shock and shame&quot;&gt;&quot;shock&quot; customers, &quot;shame&quot; the companies&lt;/a&gt;, and &quot;confuse&quot; customers. &amp;nbsp;It has &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2010/01/google-and-china-the-attacks-and-their-aftermath.ars&quot; title=&quot;ars&quot;&gt;been reported&lt;/a&gt; that &quot;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial, sans-serif; color: #333333; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;Sprint&amp;rsquo;s head of legal compliance revealed that their automated system had processed 8 million requests for GPS location data in the span of a year, noting that it would have been impossible to manually serve that level of law enforcement traffic&quot;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial, sans-serif; color: #333333;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;Now, it looks as if the cat is out of the bag. It's not clear at this point why Google decided to publicly disclose the nature of the breach instead of keeping communications private. &amp;nbsp;As the story develops, it will be interesting to see how this mix of statecraft and enterprise business plays out. However, when viewed in conjunction with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Military/2009/1231/CIA-agents-killed-in-Afghanistan-were-in-Taliban-s-backyard&quot; title=&quot;cia&quot;&gt;recent killing of CIA agents&lt;/a&gt; in Afghanistan, it is clear that an active surveillance and counter-terrorism policy doesn't come without consequences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial, sans-serif; color: #333333;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;The question of whether the consequences are worth the benefits is a matter for public policy debate. &amp;nbsp;In a way, the data breach at Google is a good thing, because it has generated broader public debate about the role of corporate america in statecraft, and whether US companies should make moral judgments in the conduct of their business. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fortunesmallbusiness.com/2009/10/16/news/economy/mbas_ethics_classes.fortune/index.htm&quot; title=&quot;MBA ethics&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;It's worth talking about.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why people pay for webapps ... a customer perspective.</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/why-people-pay-for-webapps-a-customer-perspec/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-11T04:58:38-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/why-people-pay-for-webapps-a-customer-perspec/why-people-pay-for-webapps-a-customer-perspec</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the thing that boggles me completely are people actually paying money for some dead simple applications. ... Are there not sufficient free open source tools to monitor your server and mail you when it goes down? Why would some of those big ticket customers ever pay for something like this? ...&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
						
						
						
            
          						
						
						

						
						
            
              
            
          
					&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://akshat.posterous.com/why-do-people-pay-for-webapps&quot;&gt;akshat.posterous.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was reading the original poster's question and left a quick comment, but I also felt like this was a question worth responding to more fully.  So I'm going to address it here. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me, the short answer is that pople can be enticed to pay for webapps when the app delivers value and solves a problem. Open source tools all too often solve a problem, but do so in a way that fails to deliver value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting things about the &quot;app&quot; development model that's taking off in the mobile and web spaces is that it breaks down the barriers to entrepreneurship.  Anyone with the skills to write some code and use that code to implement an idea can create an app.  In some cases, this causes an explosion of competition that eventually settles down to a more natural oligopoly.  But it also presents an opportunity for entrepreneurs to bring their unique value proposition to market and allow market forces to select which solution delivers more value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because someone else has built an app in your space for free, or even if an open source product exists, does not mean that a paid app can't be a huge success.  Apple didn't make the first smartphone.  Blizzard's World of Warcraft wasn't the first MMO.  But both turned out to be hugely profitable projects because the vision that was implemented created [b]value[/b].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One example from my personal workflow is Dropbox.  I'm a paid subscriber to that service, which allows me to synchronize certain files between computers I own.  I can also share those files with others.  Dropbox isn't doing any magic that couldn't already be built from other solutions.  They use Amazon's cloud (EBS I think) and a software client.  You can build the same thing from open source tools like rsync, saving to an S3 or webdav instance.  But the beauty of Dropbox is that you don't have to. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where the great webapps deliver value isn't in the technical implementation, it's in the removal of barriers to entry for their customers.  I signed up for dropbox because it took less than two minutes and solved an immediate problem.  Sure, I could have built something on my own the following weekend in less than a day, but I had a need (synching a file) and wanted it solved immediately.  I signed up for the free trial, and Dropbox did a sufficiently good job that I a) kept my account active and b) paid money for the upsell.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For certain customers, there's a difference between &quot; I can do this myself &quot; and &quot;It's worth it for me to do this myself&quot;.   Open source solutions usually fall into the first category.  Paid apps allow customers to answer no to the second question.  As long as customers are willing to hire you to solve their problem in less time than it would take them on their own, then you have a market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>User Experience Matters: What Lawyers Can Learn From “Objectified”</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/user-experience-matters-what-lawyers-can-lear/index.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-04T10:27:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/user-experience-matters-what-lawyers-can-lear/user-experience-matters-what-lawyers-can-lear</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;posterous_long_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of what we seem to be doing in a product like that is getting design out of the way&lt;/strong&gt;. With that sort of reason,&lt;strong&gt; it feels almost inevitable, almost undesigned and it feels almost, like of course it is that way. Why would it be any other way&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2010/01/03/objectified-design/&quot;&gt;gigaom.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What in the world does consumer product design have to do with practicing law?  Quite a bit, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the design of your legal writing &quot;get out of the way&quot;, or does it beat your reader over the head every time a passage is read?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had the experience of going into a court hearing, and the Judge was receiving written briefs from multiple parties.  One of the lawyers handed over a very short (couple of pages) memo.  The Judge smiled, extended his hands, placing the short memo in one hand, and weighing it like a scale.   Maybe the memo was too short, maybe it wasn't thorough, but the initial reaction was one of surprise and created a moment of levity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not proposing that we give our arguments or work product short shrift.  But, attorney work product is just that:&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;a product&lt;/strong&gt;.  If the client or the court or even the opponent can't make heads nor tails of it on account of impermeable language or heft then much of the time (and, by way of billable hours, money) has been wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try reading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2010/01/03/objectified-design/&quot; title=&quot;linked article (gigaom.com)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;linked&lt;/a&gt; and think of it in terms of a legal product rather than a consumer product.  Can you say that your &quot;users react positively when things are clear and understandable&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I reacted strongly upon hearing the comment that &quot;&lt;em&gt;It is important to remember things that are important and not important and then removing things that are vying for your attention&lt;/em&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does your legal writing do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Snippets of Wisdom: What Avatar reviews tell us about inventiveness.</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/snippets-of-wisdom-what-avatar-reviews-tell-u/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-22T04:15:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/snippets-of-wisdom-what-avatar-reviews-tell-u/snippets-of-wisdom-what-avatar-reviews-tell-u</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;posterous_long_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avatar &lt;/em&gt;isn't the first 3D film - or the first sci-fi film - to tackle issues of colonialism, and neither is it the first to feature CGI characters. If the set-up of the movie had been &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; original, not even Cameron could have got such lavish backing for it. The game-changer must be the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt;, not the newest. It must take familiar and popular elements to a new level. The previous two game-changers were not distinguished by their originality, but by their extraordinary invention and their capacity to place a new spin on what had gone before.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shadowlocked.com/index.php/component/content/article/41-feature/71-why-avatar-cant-join-star-wars-and-jurassic-park-as-a-game-changer&quot;&gt;shadowlocked.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this gem in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shadowlocked.com/index.php/component/content/article/41-feature/71-why-avatar-cant-join-star-wars-and-jurassic-park-as-a-game-changer#&quot; title=&quot;a review&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a review&lt;/a&gt; of James Cameron's new movie Avatar. It's certainly not the first time I've read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/forbes/2007/0618/154.html&quot; title=&quot;variations&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;variations&lt;/a&gt; on&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-mover_advantage&quot; title=&quot; this view&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; this view&lt;/a&gt; of commercially successful innovators.  But it bears repeating.  The first-mover advantage doesn't mean much if your implementation isn't great.  In fact, innovators face a tremendous challenge overcoming inertia.  That's why Hollywood sequels are such a mainstay of box office commercialism.  People know what they're getting and it doesn't require much cognitive effort from buyers to make the 'safe' choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the lesson I take from these kind of examples is that you really need to focus on what your product does for the end-user, not necessarily what new technology is under the covers.  The really great products take a technology that is new (but not-quite-bleeding-edge) and combine it with a deep understanding of what problems it can solve for the viewer, user, or buyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/magazine/2009/12/fail_duke_nukem/&quot; title=&quot;Just don't overdo it.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Just don't overdo it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time Warner's Bogus Pricing Campaign</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/time-warners-bogus-pricing-campaign/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-18T06:33:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/time-warners-bogus-pricing-campaign/time-warners-bogus-pricing-campaign</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 11px; line-height: 17px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;posterous_medium_quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically,&amp;nbsp;[Time Warner]&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;saying they face increasing contract prices when it comes time to renewing their content deals, and they&amp;rsquo;re telling me, their customer, that they may have to raise prices on my service if I want to keep getting the same programming that I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten before. In essence, they&amp;rsquo;re trying to say that it&amp;rsquo;s not their fault that prices will be going up &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s those evil content providers who are fleecing the innocent Time Warner. And if they do raise prices, it&amp;rsquo;ll be my fault as a customer &amp;mdash; I should have supported them when I wanted them to get tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a complete crock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mikeschramm.com/general/roll-over-or-roll-over-20091208&quot;&gt;mikeschramm.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going to write a post on my thoughts about Time Warner's new price hike campaign, but then I ran across this post by Mike Schramm that says everything I wanted to say.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mikeschramm.com/general/roll-over-or-roll-over-20091208&quot; title=&quot;So take a look.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;So take a look.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Steve On Randall Stephenson of AT&T</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/fake-steve-on-randall-stephenson-of-att/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-17T02:56:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/fake-steve-on-randall-stephenson-of-att/fake-steve-on-randall-stephenson-of-att</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpwwwfakestevenetwpcontentthemesfakesteveimgfakestevepng_tJnqHykoFJyuyAH.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fake Steve On Randall Stephenson of AT&amp;T&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fakesteve.net/2009/12/a-not-so-brief-chat-with-randall-stephenson-of-att.html&quot;&gt;fakesteve.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent rant, extreme language notwithstanding. The question is, when the Giants fall, who will stand up in their place?  When the dinosaurs were eliminated, it was the nimble mammals that supplanted them.  Startups and small businesses are the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dpc.senate.gov/docs/fs-111-1-152.html&quot; title=&quot;engine of our economy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;engine of our economy&lt;/a&gt;.  Think nimble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2009 Patents Word Cloud - Who doesn't need a Bacon Comb ?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/2009-patents-word-cloud-who-doesnt-need-a-bac/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-17T01:38:47-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/2009-patents-word-cloud-who-doesnt-need-a-bac/2009-patents-word-cloud-who-doesnt-need-a-bac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpgraphics8nytimescomimages20091213magazine13endpaperpopupjpg_lsbAEsdpBDtcHbB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2009 Patents Word Cloud - Who doesn't need a Bacon Comb ?&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/imagepages/2009/12/13/magazine/13endpaper.html?src=tptw&quot;&gt;nytimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I got a good laugh out of some of these.  Patentable doesn't necessarily = marketable.  Well, that and I'm probably just not the target market for a leg mounted scent dispenser.  I may need a Bacon Comb though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google Phone a disruptive force ... in a way the iPhone should have been years ago.</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/google-phone-a-disruptive-force-in-a-way-the/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-15T02:29:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/google-phone-a-disruptive-force-in-a-way-the/google-phone-a-disruptive-force-in-a-way-the</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpwwwandroidguyscomwpcontentuploads200912nexus21287x300jpg_IApAjoiFHydyBwx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google Phone a disruptive force ... in a way the iPhone should have been years ago.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidguys.com/2009/12/14/reuters-nexus-one-available-directly-through-google-website-january-5/&quot;&gt;androidguys.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Steve Jobs introduced the iPhone, Apple had an opportunity to disrupt the entire mobile ecosystem.  Instead, they chose to tie the JesusPhone to AT&amp;amp;T, a carrier that is often viewed as more devil than angel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Google's Nexus One phone promises to do for carrier relationships what the iPhone never did.  Unlike the iPhone that debuted at nearly $600 and is now available in refurb trim at $99, Google is coming right out of the gate with a $199/99 price.  That means that an unsubsidized phone is within reach of most smartphone consumers and many others who would have been stuck with a traditional phone or a long contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not the most revolutionary part.  If news reports are to be believed, &quot;Google will push full VOIP usage on these, meaning no voice/sms plans needed at any carrier.&quot; Reports also claims that &quot;Voice calls will go through Google Voice on Data SIM cards and will provide unlimited free voice calling. And SMS is replaced by unlimited free Gtalk.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a huge shift, and if it's implemented right, could change the landscape of smartphones.  It's also a huge risk for Google.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/techbeat/archives/2009/10/google_voice_at.html&quot; title=&quot;Google and AT&amp;amp;T&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google and AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; have already found themselves at loggerheads &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;amp;rls=en&amp;amp;q=google+at%26t+fcc&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;oe=UTF-8&quot; title=&quot;with the FCC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with the FCC&lt;/a&gt; over common carrier requirements. Use of VOIP on the Google Phone is certain to inflame the situation further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also threatens the cash-cow SMS market if the Google Talk functions implement an SMS gateway and a UI that makes it easy to communicate on both Jabber/XMPP and SMS backbones.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/12/28/business/28digi.html?_r=4&quot; title=&quot;SMS is pure profit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SMS is pure profit&lt;/a&gt; and the carriers aren't likely to appreciate this encroachment on their most lucrative revenue stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if Google already has T-Mobile on board with the concept of providing essentially a data-only plan, we could see a big shake-up in the carrier landscape as providers rush to bolster their data pipeline.  Is AT&amp;amp;T likely to win that kind of war?  I certainly wouldn't put money on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can also envision a &quot;Nexus Two&quot; in the not too distant future that has a modular transceiver allowing it to operate not just on GSM/HSPDA networks but interchangeably on WiFi, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nathanroach.com/im-trying-clearcom-clearwire-4g-wimax-interne&quot; title=&quot;WiMax&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;WiMax&lt;/a&gt;, LTE, and other 4G technologies.  At this point, the carrier's signally method makes far less of a difference and the carrier basically becomes a dumb conduit for your IP-based bitstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus question: if the Nexus One really does signal a shift to data service as the sole function of a carrier, does that portend a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.broadbandreports.com/shownews/ATT-Hints-At-UsageBased-iPhone-Data-Pricing-105900&quot; title=&quot;shift to usage-based data billing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shift to usage-based data billing&lt;/a&gt;?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>RT: The impact of language choice on github projects</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/rt-the-impact-of-language-choice-on-github-pr/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-14T01:30:30-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/rt-the-impact-of-language-choice-on-github-pr/rt-the-impact-of-language-choice-on-github-pr</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;blockquote class=&quot;posterous_short_quote&quot;&gt;This shows the number of swearwords used per 1000 commits. Objective C and Perl
programmers are the most foul-mouthed. Java coders are more restrained,
possibly because the language is more corporate, and they're afraid of having
their pay docked.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://corte.si/posts/code/devsurvey/index.html&quot;&gt;corte.si&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The author of this article sifted through  5000 repositories on GitHub, producing about 55G of data, correlating several factors with choice of language.  The analysis covered C, C#, C++, Java, Javascript, Objective-C, Perl, Python, and Ruby, among others.  The results were interesting and produced both useful and entertaining correlations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The patent system: Mend it, don't end it.</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/the-patent-system-mend-it-dont-end-it/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-11T06:55:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/the-patent-system-mend-it-dont-end-it/the-patent-system-mend-it-dont-end-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article on the patent system really sets me off. The problem with the patent system is not that the system as a whole is fatally flawed. The problem surrounds term and enablement. The term problem is even worse in copyright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article states that &quot;Ideas kept under lock and key are much less useful than those that are freely available.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's precisely the point of the patent system. It is supposed to encourage disclosure so that after the protected period the knowledge is made fully available to society.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;The alternative is trade secret protection whereby inventors remain secretive about their work product, never disclosing to the public at large how the device works and not allowing follow-ons to build upon their knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;The two problems with the current system are 1) protection terms are too long and 2) the enablement requirements aren't enforced well enough.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Let's say that the protection term is reduced to one year. And assume that the USPTO requires patents with sufficient detail to fully enable readers to replicate and practice the invention.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Under that scenario, I think that the patent system would be seen as an asset to society. In exchange for a year's worth of protection the inventor has to tell society explicitly how to do exactly what he or she is doing. I don't think most people would have a problem with that system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;If you go back to the Constitutional basis for the patent system, it was &quot;To promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, by securing for limited Times to Authors and Inventors the exclusive Right to their respective Writings and Discoveries.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as &quot;limited time&quot; is a reasonable period, I don't know that abolition is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial, Tahoma, Verdana, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; color: #333333; line-height: 22px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h1 class=&quot;head&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-bottom: 0.25em; margin-left: 0px; font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, Times, serif; line-height: 1.2; font-weight: normal; font-size: 32px; padding: 0px;&quot;&gt;The patent system: End it, don't mend it&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;subhead&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 0px; padding: 0px;&quot;&gt;From AIDS to Android phones, research shows that intellectual property rights are detrimental to the social good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;St. Louis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common to argue that intellectual property (IP) in the form of copyrights and patents is crucial for the creation of innovative ideas and inventions such as machines, drugs, software, books, and music. Proponents argue that IP is just like ordinary property in houses and cars. In fact, empirical evidence shows that IP does not promote innovation and that, unlike ordinary property, it is detrimental to the social good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/Commentary/Opinion/2009/1208/p09s06-coop.html&quot;&gt;csmonitor.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I'm trying Clear.com / Clearwire 4G WiMAX Internet</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/im-trying-clearcom-clearwire-4g-wimax-interne/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-09T03:56:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/im-trying-clearcom-clearwire-4g-wimax-interne/im-trying-clearcom-clearwire-4g-wimax-interne</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;I decided to try Clear.com's 4G WiMax service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Managing Expectations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Current Alternatives:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium; font-style: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;I live in an area with pretty basic Internet access. &amp;nbsp;Time Warner Cable supplies cable internet with a burst speed of 20mbps down and 2 up. &amp;nbsp;I usually get 10-15 sustained down and I'm lucky to see 1 up. &amp;nbsp;AT&amp;amp;T offers its U-Verse product in our city, but haven't built it out to our older neighborhood yet, so the only option from them is DSL. &amp;nbsp;Both AT&amp;amp;T and Time Warner have absolutely frightening 2-year contracts, although Time Warner calls theirs a &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timewarnercable.com/centraltx/learn/bundles/plgterms.html&quot; title=&quot;price lock guarantee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;price lock guarantee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&quot; instead of a contract. &amp;nbsp;They should call it a &quot;customer lock extortion&quot; instead. &amp;nbsp;I've been with them on a month-to-month plan for some time and my bill fluctuates monthly with a general upward trend. &amp;nbsp;I've desperately wanted to decouple my TV and Internet because Time Warner has this clever policy where they give you a &quot;discount&quot; on your internet for having TV service. &amp;nbsp;Which means that if you just want to buy an internet line, it costs you just as much as buying internet and TV together.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some Concerns on Clear's Terms of Service:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;When I heard about Clear.com building out &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WiMAX&quot; title=&quot;WiMAX&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;WiMax&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt; in my area, I was ecstatic. I'm under no illusions that Clear (previously Clearwire) is some kind of savior or game-changer. &amp;nbsp;They're &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://newsreleases.sprint.com/phoenix.zhtml?c=127149&amp;amp;p=irol-newsArticle_newsroom&amp;amp;ID=1141088&quot; title=&quot;largely owned by Sprint&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;largely owned by Sprint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;, a company that has &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-10004328-38.html&quot; title=&quot;been found&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;been found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt; to enforce unconscionable contracts on its customers. &amp;nbsp;My own history with them validates that finding, although I haven't monitored the case to see if/how the appellate process turned out. &amp;nbsp;However, given the number of home visits I've required from Time Warner just to get basic things like cable-card support working I was ready to try out someone new. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;The User Experience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Give it a Go, Quickly:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Clear doesn't give you a very broad window to decide if the service is to your liking. &amp;nbsp;I think you get five or seven days before you're bound (like the others) into a two-year contract. &amp;nbsp;They also do some sneaky things like requiring you agree to a TOS which states you agree to their ETF, but then you have to call them to actually find out the ETF (which also makes it hard to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tzlegal.com/clearwire.asp&quot; title=&quot;prove in court&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;prove in court&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt; if they &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://clearwiresucks.com/blog/2009/04/22/lawsuit-filed-against-clearwire/&quot; title=&quot;try to screw you later&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;try to screw you later&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;). &amp;nbsp;I did call customer service before signing up, and the rep was very friendly but lied to me directly claiming that I could &quot;save big money&quot; signing up through him rather than the web site. &amp;nbsp;He said it would take weeks to receive my equipment from the web site and that I'd have to pay for shipping. &amp;nbsp;Neither of which was true.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Fast Shipping, (mostly) Fast Internet:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Despite the rep's (commissioned?) pleas to sign up by phone, I placed my order through the web site. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;I signed up via their web site Monday afternoon and had the equipment at my door the very next day. &amp;nbsp;The equipment was well boxed and already provisioned so setup was literally a plug-and-go affair. &amp;nbsp;I chose the bundle of home, mobile, and voice.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Image credit: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/testing-clears-wimax-internet-service/&quot; title=&quot;Digital Trends&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.digitaltrends.com/images/features/testing-clears-wimax-internet-service/2.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;The broadband modem for home use required two plugs, one for ethernet and one for power. &amp;nbsp;Within 2 minutes I had a signal and was connected to the internet via my router. &amp;nbsp;My average latency was 120ms, up from about 40ms on cable. &amp;nbsp;Download speed ranged widely from about 3mbs to 7mbs. &amp;nbsp;Upload was even less than cable, delivering 400kbps vs 800kbps previously. &amp;nbsp;In actual usage though, the speed differences weren't obtrusive. &amp;nbsp;Unlike 3G via my iPhone, the WiMax 4G felt like wired internet. &amp;nbsp;I was even able to get in a bit of MMORPG gaming and the lag was tolerable, delivering about 200ms in-game. &amp;nbsp;While this objectively this seems like a lot more than the 70ms I saw on cable, it didn't feel that way. &amp;nbsp;Not to mention I've seen lag-storms of 2500ms+ on roadrunner in the past (based on my neighbors' usage?). &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;The mobile installation is almost as easy. &amp;nbsp;In the box is the USB receiver, an elbow adapter, and a USB drive with the connection manager software. &amp;nbsp;Well, the software for PC that is. &amp;nbsp;For my Macbook Pro, I needed to visit their site and download the connection manager. &amp;nbsp;Fortunately, it was an easy install and the software explicitly lists compatibility with Snow Leopard. &amp;nbsp;Installation didn't require a reboot and I was quickly in business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Overall, the speeds aren't going to blow you away if compared to wired internet, but they are very reasonable. &amp;nbsp;And for the price, I'd say it's quite a deal. &amp;nbsp;$70 a month covers me for home, mobile, and VOIP. &amp;nbsp;That's less than I was paying for home service alone from the cable company. &amp;nbsp;I lose out on a little bit of speed, but that seems a reasonable trade-off for the flexibility and superior mobile speed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Edit:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt; I found a review from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/testing-clears-wimax-internet-service/&quot; title=&quot;Digital Trends&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: medium;&quot;&gt; that goes into a bit more detail on the user experience, and my observations are consistent with their findings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Playing Catch-Up: A counterpoint to this Dilbert comic</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/playing-catch-up-a-counterpoint-to-this-dilbe/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-09T01:57:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/playing-catch-up-a-counterpoint-to-this-dilbe/playing-catch-up-a-counterpoint-to-this-dilbe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpdilbertcomdynstrstrip0000000000000000000000000000007000050009007599075990stripprintgif_FjtxfnknqxJdtAA.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Playing Catch-Up: A counterpoint to this Dilbert comic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://dilbert.com/fast/2009-12-09/&quot;&gt;dilbert.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Dilbert comic was referenced on &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=985875&quot;&gt;HN&lt;/a&gt; recently.  I got a good laugh out of it and have spent enough time in a developer role to appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after the initial laugh, I recognized some painful similarities between the PHB's request and the situation that many startups and small businesses find themselves in.  There's something to be said for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-mover_advantage&quot;&gt;first-mover-advantage&lt;/a&gt; but it's not a holy grail.  It's been said a number of times that if you're first to market and have no competition, maybe there isn't really a market there.  To some extent, the presence of competition validates the viability of your market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what then is a new entrant to do?  Invariably you'll need to address the competition's feature matrix when you start pitching to customers.  Many profitable entrepreneurs have succeeded by recognizing a need or source of intense pain within an existing industry and change the game by introducing a novel solution to that need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if a client's basic needs remain unsatisfied it doesn't matter how cool your product is.  Put another way, if you solve one problem while re-introducing several others you have an uphill battle to generate a significant conversion rate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;&quot;&gt;Maybe you don't have to match the competition feature-for-feature, but you do need to match them need-for-need.  If you don't address customer needs, good luck with your conversion rate.  And in the end, a feature matrix is just one company's articulation of what it thinks those customer needs are.  Maybe you disagree or maybe you have a better way, but if the same 70% of features show up over and over again amongst your competition, you'd better find a way to satisfy those needs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the lesson from this comic shouldn't dissuade entrepreneurs from attacking an established market.  Yes, you will have to work day and night to match your competitor's features (or the core set of them that matter).  But as long as you carve out sufficient time to develop your own vision in tandem, some time spent on &quot;legacy&quot; features can make it much easier for customers to bridge from their old solution to your invention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google Goggles Image Search: A killer app for mobile?</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/google-goggles-image-search-a-killer-app-for/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-07T07:41:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/google-goggles-image-search-a-killer-app-for/google-goggles-image-search-a-killer-app-for</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media_httpwwwgooglecommobileimageslabsgogglesgoggleslandmarkjpg_GJqywCqGxjguCdD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google Goggles Image Search: A killer app for mobile?&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/mobile/goggles/#book&quot;&gt;google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to be able to point your phone at something you see and instantly know more about it? &amp;nbsp;That futuristic vision is fast approaching due to Google Goggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, one great advantage to Apple's iPhone app store is that it allowed small developers with innovative ideas to reach an audience that they would have had a hard time attracting on their own.  Say what you want about the App Store's developer policies, innovators like Red Laser (&lt;a href=&quot;http://redlaser.com/)&quot;&gt;http://redlaser.com/)&lt;/a&gt; have created some very useful apps that let you do things with a mobile platform that would have been impossible previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you're an innovator, you have to keep moving or the big guys will catch up.  And if you have someone like Google in your market, that's all the more important.  Google's foundation comes from innovation and the 20% time policies promote experimentation (ie: the Google holodeck &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/31/video-inside-the-google-holodeck/).&lt;/p&quot;&gt;http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/31/video-inside-the-google-holodeck/).&lt;/p&lt;/a&gt;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, Google has done it again with Google Goggles (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/mobile/goggles/#book&quot;&gt;google.com&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;nbsp;and built upon a number of pre-existing technologies to come up with a transformative way of using your mobile phone.  Just about any device with a camera and a web browser should eventually be able to give you results.  No text entry, dialing, or voice navigation required. &amp;nbsp;This technology was announced recently at a Google&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/12/07/google-search-event/&quot;&gt;Search Event&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and is Android-only for the moment. &amp;nbsp;Which means that users of the HTC Dream, T-Mobile G1, Motorola Droid and others will be getting the jump on iPhone users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward, as they refine the algorithms behind this search (and employ crowd-sourcing to boost accuracy like they do with Captchas) I can see this becoming the default input method for many mobile queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if only my iPhone's camera wasn't so terrible...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Passion. Beauty.  And lots of Hardware.  </title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/passion-beauty-and-lots-of-hardware/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-05T05:55:20-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/passion-beauty-and-lots-of-hardware/passion-beauty-and-lots-of-hardware</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;object height=&quot;417&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/cz3Ng1eUHrw&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;wmode&quot; value=&quot;window&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/cz3Ng1eUHrw&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&quot; wmode=&quot;window&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; height=&quot;417&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cz3Ng1eUHrw&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&quot;&gt;youtube.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A french director has sought to bring the passion and glory of racing at the Nurburgring circuit to life on the big screen. Based on this HD preview on YouTube, I'd say the director's vision is well on its way to bringing this iconic circuit to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Terms of Use Agreement - MOG</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/terms-of-use-agreement-mog/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-04T10:16:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/terms-of-use-agreement-mog/terms-of-use-agreement-mog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;Ok, this is one of the more entertaining Terms of Service that I've had to soldier through. When you read this stuff for a living, it's nice to encounter legalese with a sense of humor. &amp;nbsp;Oh, and check out their Board of Directors. &amp;nbsp;They've got some heavyweights playing this game of ball. &amp;nbsp;It's about time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MOG and All Access Terms of Use &amp;amp; your End-User License Agreement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ WELL. THIS MOG, INC. (&quot;MOG&quot; ALSO BETTER KNOWN AS &quot;WE,&quot; &quot;US,&quot; OR &quot;OUR&quot;) AND ALL ACCESS END USER LICENSE AGREEMENT (&quot;AGREEMENT&quot;) IS A LEGAL AND BINDING AGREEMENT BETWEEN YOU (&quot;YOU&quot; &amp;amp; &quot;YOUR&quot;) AND MOG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WE DON'T WANT YOU TO STOP.  WE WANT YOU TO USE OUR STUFF.  BUT IF YOU DON'T AGREE, YOU ARE NOT AUTHORIZED TO USE ANY APPLICATION AND YOU GOTTA PROMPTLY CEASE USING SOFTWARE OR CONTENT THAT YOU GOT FROM US THAT MAY STILL BE IN YOUR POSSESSION, AND YOU CAN'T ACCESS ALL THIS COOL CONTENT WE'RE WORKING SO HARD TO MAKE AVAILABLE TO YOU. IF YOU DON'T OR CAN'T ABIDE BY THE TERMS WE ARE OFFERING YOU FOR THIS AWESOME SERVICE AND PRODUCTS, WE WON'T BE (TOO) HURT, BUT WE MAY HAVE TO TERMINATE YOUR ACCESS (W/O ANY PREJUDICE, EXTREME OR OTHERWISE) TO THE APPLICATION(S), THE ALL ACCESS SERVICE (&quot;SERVICE&quot;), ANY RELATED MOG SERVICE, SITE AND/OR ANY CONTENT OR PART THEREOF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get to what MOG (and All Access) are all about-some more legal descriptions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;MOG is all-powerful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that MOG retains all of the legal rights to control its site, service and membership. That means that MOG has the absolute right to unilaterally delete anything that is posted to any webpage, and to terminate your account at any time for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MOG is powerless&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOG recognizes that its users have significant power and control regarding what is posted on it. Despite retaining total legal control, MOG has neither the ability nor the desire to monitor all posts at all times. And, even if MOG does become aware of a particular post, MOG may not remove the post when others think that it should. As such, MOG assumes no obligation to monitor or control what Content is posted. MOG cannot be responsible for the accuracy or opinions of what is posted on it. Nor can MOG be responsible for what its advertisers promote or sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MOG owns intellectual property&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content created by MOG belongs to MOG and is protected by copyright, trademark, patent, trade secret and other laws. MOG owns and retains all rights in content created by MOG. MOG grants you a limited, revocable, non-sub-licensable license to reproduce and display Content (excluding MOG's software code) solely for your individual use when using MOG. You do not have the right to reproduce, distribute, modify, translate, publish, broadcast, transmit, perform, display, or sell any Content appearing on or through MOG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MOG doesn't play well with countries who are on a shitlist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Application is provided with restricted rights. Use, duplication or disclosure by the Government is subject to restrictions as set forth in subparagraph (c)(1)(ii) of The Rights in Technical Data and Computer Software clause of DFARS 252.227-7013 or subparagraphs (c)(i) and (2) of the Commercial Computer Software-Restricted Rights at 48 CFR 52.227-19, as applicable. Manufacturer of Application is ________. You acknowledge that none of the Application may be downloaded or otherwise exported or re-exported (i) into (or to a national or resident of) Cuba, Iraq, Libya, North Korea, Iran, Serbia (except Kosovo), Sudan, Syria, or any other country to which the U.S. has embargoed goods; or (ii) to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department's list of Specially Designated Nationals or the U.S. Commerce Department's Denied Parties List or Entity List. By using the Application you are agreeing to the foregoing and are representing and warranting that you are not located in, under the control of, or a national or resident of, any such country or on any such list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MOG is in CaliMOGia (actually, it's in California)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a dispute between you and MOG, it shall be resolved by a court in California applying the laws of California without regard for conflicts of law. Further, you agree to personal jurisdiction by and venue in the state and federal courts of California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USE OF LYRICS VIA MOG REQUIRES ACCEPTANCE OF THE TERMS BELOW. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS, YOU MUST NOT USE LYRICS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To Sum It Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This TOU/EULA Agreement applies whether you are simply visiting a MOG site, using any MOG application (including All Access) or whether you simply choose to participate in the MOG community without accessing all that other good stuff we offer.  And to be clear, this Agreement applies to all aspects of MOG, including the use of its website(s) and its client Applications, from now until eternity. And, this Agreement does not replace other MOG policies (including the Privacy Policy, available here). Users must also understand that they are agreeing to MOG's Privacy Policy and, if appropriate, the MOG-O-MATIC End User License Agreement. Just as in any committed relationship, the rules may change over time (though we always try to be reasonable, and we are definitely committed&amp;mdash;to you and your experience). As such, you must understand that MOG may reasonably change this Agreement from time to time, and that you will be bound by any revisions. Your continued use of an Application or our Site following our posting of a change of terms notice or a new End User License Agreement for an Application will constitute your binding acceptance of the change. YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS AGREEMENT INDICATES THAT YOU GIVE CONSENT TO MOG TO E-MAIL YOU WITH NOTICES CONCERNING MATERIAL CHANGES IN TERMS OF THIS AGREEMENT, AN APPLICATION OR SERVICES TO WHICH YOU SUBSCRIBE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If MOG is not for you or you do not agree to any of the terms set forth above, please do not visit our website(s), participate in the community or use MOG-O-MATIC.  In other words, buh-bye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://mog.com/terms_of_use&quot;&gt;mog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>MOG Internet Radio</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/mog-internet-radio/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-04T10:11:29-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/mog-internet-radio/mog-internet-radio</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;http://images0.mog.com/images/promos/radio_hdr.png?1259764906&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;43&quot; alt=&quot;Radio_hdr&quot; width=&quot;92&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Listen only to your favorite artist, or mix in songs from similar artists&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;em&gt;unrestricted radio&lt;/em&gt;. See what songs are coming up next, or jump back and listen to a track again. &lt;em&gt;Music plays non-stop&lt;/em&gt;, even in on-demand mode where you can select individual albums or songs to listen to. As your selection of songs comes to an end, we add similar songs to your queue so your listening experience isn’t interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://mog.com/promos/overview&quot;&gt;mog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ok, this is seriously cool.  I've tried Last.fm and Pandora in the past and while they have their place, I was always frustrated by their limitations.  It felt more like the labels were making me listen to what they wanted, not what I was after.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure, MOG's a pay service, but $5/mo is very fair.  If you buy much iTunes music, you'll clear that price very quickly.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drawback is that even with their Library feature, you don't really own a license to the music that survives beyond the service.  So, if you cancel your account, or if their Terms of Service changes, if they go out of business, or just decide to raise prices, you don't get to keep any of the music.  But many people are fine with this model and are willing to make the trade-off just as they do with Netflix or Blockbuster subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You also can't download the music to your iPod or MP3 player because its streaming.  They do have an iPhone client and I would expect that over the course of time, streaming is going to become even more pervasive.  If Boxee/XMBC,  Android, and other devices can tie in to the service then they'll really have a strong contender in MOG.  Certainly Google is betting on cloud-based data with their ChromeOS and this is no different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think it's worth the tradeoffs and limitations if you have even a modest monthly music budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vark.com Provides Answers (but is it better than Google?)</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/varkcom-provides-answers-but-is-it-better-tha/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-04T05:20:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/varkcom-provides-answers-but-is-it-better-tha/varkcom-provides-answers-but-is-it-better-tha</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I signed up for Aardvark (vark.com) recently and have been using it for about a month now. My question to answer ratio is skewed significantly towards answers, mostly because I'm still able to find most of what I need to know via Google or Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I can see value in using this service as a sounding board or for questions that require a subjective answer. It's also good for questioners who prefer plain-language questions over trying to construct a seach query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, Vark asks me 2-4 questions per day and the majority of them are technology related. If you're like me and wind up acting as a tech support department for family and friends, you might be able to offload a lot of that work to Vark by directing your &quot;user base&quot; to Vark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vark also has a great &quot;answer, busy, pass&quot; function. When you get a question if you don't have time to answer you can just tell it busy or pass and it will direct the question to someone else. I find I'm much more willing to do a little research and answer a question when it comes with no strings attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, Aardvark isn't going to replace your existing research sources but it's a fun tool that might just help you get answers to a question you wouldn't otherwise take the time to find on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My vark.com link is &lt;a href=&quot;http://vark.com/s/Br9k&quot;&gt;http://vark.com/s/Br9k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's a review of the service from NY Times correspondent David Pogue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of nastiness on the Internet&amp;ndash;mean stuff, dirty stuff, snarky stuff&amp;ndash;but there&amp;rsquo;s also an incredible amount of kindness and support to be found. Next time you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something wildly entertaining and enlightening to do online, check out a site like &lt;a href=&quot;http://answers.yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;answers.yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.answerbag.com/&quot;&gt;answerbag.com&lt;/a&gt;. On these sites, you can pose a question&amp;ndash;any question at all&amp;ndash;and crowdsource the answer. You watch and wait as the vast masses chime in with their opinions on your questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, I&amp;rsquo;d been relying on Twitter for all my obscure-question-answering needs. Often I&amp;rsquo;d ask for help on some tweaky Photoshop filter setting or a detail of some 1950&amp;rsquo;s Broadway show&amp;ndash;and sure enough, someone or other would always know the answer. But often, I&amp;rsquo;d get 60 replies, meaning I&amp;rsquo;d wasted the time of 59 people&amp;ndash;and this technique doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I stumbled upon a new, better way to harness the Net for answers: &lt;a href=&quot;http://vark.com/&quot;&gt;Vark.com&lt;/a&gt;. You send your question to Aardvark (the full name of the service) using a chat program like Google Talk/Gmail Chat, AIM, MSN or Yahoo Messenger (an iPhone app is coming soon), where you&amp;rsquo;ve added Aardvark as a buddy. You can also send a question by e-mail to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:aardvark@vark.com&quot;&gt;aardvark@vark.com&lt;/a&gt; or on Twitter. At the moment, you have to have a Facebook account before you can get started; that&amp;rsquo;s how Aardvark gets its initial idea of your social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service makes no attempt to blanket the Internet with your question. In fact, it forwards your question only to people who have specifically declared themselves to have expertise on your subject&amp;ndash;and, furthermore, only people who are already in your online social circle. If there&amp;rsquo;s nobody with expertise among that group, Aardvark extends its search to friends *of* your friends, and so on. Trust me, it works; I&amp;rsquo;ve never gotten a bad answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it choose who gets your question? It factors in &amp;ldquo;related topics in peoples&amp;rsquo; profiles, how you&amp;rsquo;re connected to people, who you trust about related topics, your history of training Aardvark, people who share your favorites (for taste-related questions), people in the right location (for location-related questions), and other mysterious factors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used Aardvark several times apiece for professional and personal queries, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been astounded by its utility every time. The answers are on my screen between 60 seconds and five minutes after I&amp;rsquo;ve asked them: private, targeted, and generally accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;posterous_quote_citation&quot;&gt;Read More via &lt;a href=&quot;http://pogue.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/09/03/got-a-burning-question-ask-the-net/&quot;&gt;pogue.blogs.nytimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.com/first-post/index.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-04T04:17:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.com/first-post/first-post-1656</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;&gt;Another Faceless Poster &lt;/span&gt;Another Face In The Crowd *&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had planned to (and will at some point) post a resume on here. &amp;nbsp;In lieu of a full CV, my next thought was short bio. &amp;nbsp;My first sentence was going to be something along the lines of &quot;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;&gt;I'm an attorney specializing in Intellectual Property Law and Business Litigation in Texas&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. &amp;nbsp;But I wound up getting hung up on the words &quot;I AM&quot;. &amp;nbsp;That's pretty heavy stuff when you think about it. &amp;nbsp;Tying one's self-identity to a license you hold or a job you do at one point in your life. &amp;nbsp;At various times in the past I could have said &quot;i am&quot; to the roles of web designer, Java programmer, PHP programmer, entrepreneur, small business owner, consultant, global traveller, lawyer, and number of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead, I'll just say that my day job is helping out startups, small businesses and innovators who have problems with&amp;nbsp;Intellectual Property Law and Business Litigation in Texas. &amp;nbsp;Most of the time that means litigation surrounding contracts, copyrights, trademarks, and patents. If you want to know more about that aspect, then you can see my firm profile at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texaslawyers.com/prinslawfirm/nathan_roach.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.texaslawyers.com/prinslawfirm/nathan_roach.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Start Now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;I've been a relatively staunch holdout on the social media and blogging trends, at least in terms of posting world-viewable information. &amp;nbsp;I'm moderately active on my facebook account, but limit the scope of my friends list there. &amp;nbsp;In part, this is because I value the public/private separation that pre-dated online social media. &amp;nbsp;And in part it is because I have a sufficiently long list of personal flaws that I don't need to add rampant narcissism to the list.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;However, I've also been trying to keep my to-do list and notes-to-self by email and in various programs on my laptop and iphone. &amp;nbsp;Invariably, the list of things I'd like to do and articles I've bookmarked gets moved, deleted, or abandoned. &amp;nbsp;So, I'm going to give this a shot via Posterous as a way to maintain a personal journal and thought organizer. &amp;nbsp;Posterous looks like a great service because of its tagging and private-post functions so it can be used as more than a general blogging platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also probably some value to be had by making some of those entries public as well. &amp;nbsp;Often, items on my personal to-do list get postponed and deferred until they've become outdated and moot. In no small part, that's because work has a way of engulfing all of my unallocated time. &amp;nbsp;In some small way, if only psychologically, making this stuff public may be an incentive to follow through on those items that might otherwise get demoted so frequently that they wind up abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I may well be the only visitor to this blog, if any of my public posts prove useful to others so much the better. &amp;nbsp;So without further ado, I guess it's time to click the &quot;Post&quot; button...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* I added a photo to my profile, necessitating an edit. &amp;nbsp;It was already on the web via&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/txtechiplaw&quot;&gt;my Twitter account&lt;/a&gt; so I don't see the harm in having it here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>